The Lannisters have declared war
on House Tyrell.
They have declared war on Dorne.
We must be allies now,
if we wish to survive.
I offer vengeance...
justice...
Fire and blood.
I traveled south
under orders
from the Lord Commander.
You ought to be a Maester.
Spending your life reading
about the achievements
of better men.
It's a map of Dragonstone.
That's dragonglass.
A mountain of it,
beneath the ground.
John needs to know.
You must send me away.
I command you to heal yourself.
I command you to find the cure.
So why's a nice girl on her own
heading to King's Landing?
I'm going to kill the queen.
I invited Euron Greyjoy,
the new king
of the Iron Islands.
The Iron Fleet is the greatest
armada Westeros has ever seen.
The surest way to
a woman's heart is with a gift.
I won't return to King's Landing
until I have that for you.
Shall we begin?
Tyrion:
On a night like this,
you came into the world.
Varys:
I remember that storm.
All the dogs in King's Landing
howled through the night.
I wish I could remember it.
I always thought
this would be a homecoming.
Doesn't feel like home.
We won't stay
on Dragonstone for long.
Good.
Daenerys:
Not so many lions.
Varys:
Cersei controls fewer
than half the Seven Kingdoms.
The lords of Westeros
despise her.
Even before your arrival,
they plotted against her.
- Now...
- They cry out
for their true queen?
They drink secret toasts
to my health?
People used to
tell my brother
that sort of thing,
and he was stupid enough
to believe them.
If Viserys had three dragons
and an army at his back,
he'd have invaded
King's Landing already.
Conquering Westeros
would be easy for you.
But you're not here
to be queen of the ashes.
No.
We can take the Seven Kingdoms
without turning it
into a slaughterhouse.
If the great houses support
your claim against Cersei,
the game is won.
With the Tyrell army
and the Dornish
on our side,
we have powerful allies
in the south.
I never properly
thanked you for that.
They joined our side, my queen,
because they believe in you.
You served my father,
didn't you, Lord Varys?
I did.
And then you served
the man who overthrew him.
I had a choice,
Your Grace...
Serve Robert Baratheon
or face the headman's axe.
But you didn't serve him long.
You turned against him.
Robert was an improvement
on your father, to be sure.
There have been
few rulers in history
as cruel as the Mad King.
Robert was
neither mad nor cruel.
He simply had no interest
in being king.
So you took it upon yourself
to find a better one.
Your Grace,
when I was
ready to drink myself
into a small coffin,
Lord Varys told me about
a queen in the east who...
Before I came to power,
you favored my brother.
All your spies,
your little birds,
did they tell you Viserys
was cruel, stupid, and weak?
Would those qualities
have made for a good king
in your learned opinion?
Until your marriage
to Khal Drogo, Your Grace,
I knew nothing about you,
save your existence
and that you were said
to be beautiful.
So you and your friends
traded me like a prized horse
to the Dothraki.
Which you turned
to your advantage.
Who gave the order to kill me?
King Robert.
Who hired the assassins?
Who sent word to Essos
to murder Daenerys Targaryen?
- Your Grace, I did
what had to be done to...
- To keep yourself alive.
Lord Varys
has proven himself
a loyal servant.
Proven himself loyal?
Quite the opposite.
If he dislikes one monarch,
he conspires to crown
the next one.
What kind of a servant is that?
The kind the realm needs.
Incompetence should not
be rewarded with
blind loyalty.
As long
as I have my eyes,
I'll use them.
I wasn't born
into a great house.
I came from nothing.
I was sold as a slave
and carved up as an offering.
When I was a child,
I lived in alleys, gutters,
abandoned houses.
You wish to know
where my true loyalties lie?
Not with any king or queen,
but with the people.
The people
who suffer under despots
and prosper under just rule.
The people whose hearts
you aim to win.
If you demand blind allegiance,
I respect your wishes.
Grey Worm can behead me
or your dragons
can devour me.
But if you let me live,
I will serve you well.
I will dedicate myself
to seeing you on
the Iron Throne
because I choose you.
Because I know the people
have no better chance
than you.
Swear this to me, Varys.
If you ever think
I'm failing the people,
you won't conspire
behind my back.
You'll look me in the eye
as you have done today,
and you'll tell me
how I'm failing them.
I swear it, my queen.
And I swear this...
If you ever betray me,
I'll burn you alive.
I would expect nothing less
from the Mother of Dragons.
Forgive me, my queen.
A red priestess from As'shai
has come to see you.
She once served another
who wanted the Iron Throne.
It didn't end well
for Stannis Baratheon,
did it?
No, it didn't.
You chose an auspicious day
to arrive at Dragonstone.
We've just decided
to pardon those
who once served the wrong king.
The Lord of Light
doesn't have many followers
in Westeros, does he?
Not yet, but even those
who don't worship the Lord
can serve his cause.
What does your lord
expect from me?
"The prince who was promised
will bring the dawn."
I'm afraid I'm not a prince.
Missandei:
Your Grace,
forgive me,
but your translation
is not quite accurate.
That noun has no gender
in High Valyrian,
so the proper translation
for that prophecy would be,
"The prince or princess
who was promised will
bring the dawn."
Doesn't really roll
off the tongue, does it?
No, but I like it better.
And you believe
this prophecy
refers to me?
Prophecies are dangerous things.
I believe you have
a role to play.
As does another...
The King in the North, Jon Snow.
Jon Snow?
- Ned Stark's bastard?
- You know him?
I travelled with him
to the Wall when he joined
the Night's Watch.
And why do you
think the Lord of Light
singled out this Jon Snow?
Aside from the visions
you've seen in the flames,
that is.
As Lord Commander
of the Night's Watch,
he allowed the wildlings
south of the Wall
to protect them
from grave danger.
As King in the North,
he has united those wildlings
with the Northern houses,
so together they may
face their common enemy.
He sounds like quite a man.
Summon Jon Snow.
Let him stand before you
and tell you the things
that have happened to him,
the things
that he has seen
with his own eyes.
I can't speak to prophecies
or visions in the flames,
but I like Jon Snow
and I trusted him.
And I am an excellent
judge of character.
If he does rule the North,
he would make a valuable ally.
The Lannisters
executed his father
and conspired
to murder his brother.
Jon Snow has even more reason
to hate Cersei than you do.
Very well.
Send a raven north.
Tell Jon Snow that his queen
invites him to come
to Dragonstone...
and bend the knee.
Gather round.
Come here.
Sansa:
You think
it's really Tyrion?
It could be someone
trying to lure you
into a trap.
Read the last bit.
"All dwarves are bastards
in their father's eyes."
What does that mean?
It's something he said to me
the first night we met.
You know him better
than any of us.
What do you think?
Tyrion's not like
the other Lannisters.
He was always kind to me,
but it's too great a risk.
"The Seven Kingdoms will bleed
as long as Cersei sits
on the Iron Throne.
Join us.
Together, we can
end her tyranny."
Sounds like a charmer.
Of course,
the casual mention
of a Dothraki horde,
a legion of Unsullied,
and three dragons...
A bit less charming.
What?
Fire kills wights, you told me.
What breathes fire?
You're not suggesting
Jon meet with her?
- No, too dangerous.
- But?
But if the Army of the Dead
makes it past the Wall,
do we have enough men
to fight them?
If the Mad King's daughter
takes the Iron Throne,
she'll destroy the realm
as we know it.
Some of you are bannermen
of House Tyrell.
But House Tyrell
is in open rebellion
against the crown.
With their help,
the Mad King's daughter
has ferried
an army of savages
to our shores...
Mindless Unsullied soldiers
who will destroy your castles
and your holdfasts,
Dothraki heathens
who will burn your
villages to the ground,
rape and enslave your women,
and butcher your children
without a second thought.
This is how Olenna Tyrell
rewards centuries of service
and loyalty.
Cersei: You all remember
the Mad King.
You remember the horrors
he inflicted upon his people.
His daughter is no different.
In Essos, her brutality
is already legendary.
She crucified
hundreds of noblemen
in Slaver's Bay.
And when she grew bored of that,
she fed them to her dragons.
It is my solemn duty
to protect the people,
and I will.
But I need your help, my lords.
We must stand together,
all of us...
if we hope to stop her.
She has three
full-grown dragons,
Your Grace.
The same as Aegon
when he conquered
the Seven Kingdoms.
How do you propose to stop them?
We are currently at work
on a solution, my lord.
Lord Tarly.
Ser Jaime.
I believe you know my son.
Rickard, isn't it?
Dickon.
That's it.
Thank you for coming.
The other lords of the Reach
look to you for guidance,
now more than ever.
They might not have come
if you hadn't.
If my queen summons me,
I answer the call.
And I've heard
what she does to
those who defy her.
You ride for Horn Hill today?
I have an army to mobilize.
Won't be long before
the fighting starts.
And which side
will you be fighting for?
You were the only man to defeat
Robert Baratheon in battle.
Not even Rhaegar Targaryen
could do that.
It's a long ride back
to the Reach, Ser Jaime.
How may I serve?
I want you to be
my ranking general
in the wars to come.
I want you to swear
allegiance to Cersei
and I want you to help me
destroy her enemies.
All her enemies.
Including Olenna Tyrell.
I'm a Tarly.
That name means something.
We're not oathbreakers.
We're not schemers.
We don't stab
our rivals in the back
or cut their throats
at weddings.
I swore an oath to House Tyrell.
You swore an oath
to the crown as well,
Lord Tarly.
I've known Olenna
since I was a child.
She was a great woman once.
Now she's broken.
She wants revenge so badly,
she brought the Dothraki
to our shores.
The Dothraki in Westeros
for the first time
in history.
I know you don't like my sister,
but you have to make a choice.
Do you fight with us
or with foreign savages
and eunuchs?
When the war is won,
the queen will need
a new Warden of the South.
I can think of no better man
than Randyll Tarly.
Ebrose:
The infection
has spread too far.
You should have
cut off your arm
the moment you were touched.
How long?
It'll be years
before it kills you.
Could be 10.
Could be 20.
But how long until...?
Your mind?
Six months, maybe fewer.
Um...
Pardon, Archmaester.
I met Stannis Baratheon's
daughter at Castle Black.
She had the greyscale
as a baby and was cured.
- Ebrose: No.
- Isn't there some way...
Ebrose:
Does this look like
a baby to you?
- No.
- Have you studied
the varying rates
of greyscale progression
in infants and fully grown men?
No.
Ebrose:
Maester Cressen discovered.
Shireen Baratheon's
affliction immediately.
This is quite advanced.
And beyond our skills, ser.
Were you a commoner,
I'd have you shipped
to Valyria at once
to live out your life
with the stone men.
As an anointed knight,
I'll allow you one more day.
How you choose
to spend that time
is up to you.
Come, Samwell.
Should we send word
to your family, Ser...?
Jorah.
Jorah Mormont.
Mormont?
There's no need.
I've been dead
to them for years.
Ebrose:
Come, Samwell!
Qyburn:
Have you ever been
down here, Your Grace?
No, I can't say I have.
I haven't seen these
since Robert had them
removed from the throne room.
Curious that King Robert
did not have them destroyed.
They were his trophies.
He couldn't keep them around.
They would have
made him look small.
Sometimes
he would come down here
and look at them.
I believe he brought
his whores on occasion.
Balerion the Dread.
The beast that Aegon
rode across the sea.
His flames forged
the Iron Throne
and brought
the Seven Kingdoms
to heel.
Powerful...
but not invincible.
Apparently,
one of Daenerys's dragons
was wounded by spears
in the fighting pits
of Meereen.
And if they can be wounded,
they can be killed.
The finest artillators
and blacksmiths in
King's Landing
have been laboring
day and night,
Your Grace.
If you'll kindly
pull that lever.
Yara:
If you want
the Iron Throne, take it.
We have an army, a fleet,
and three dragons.
We should hit
King's Landing now, hard,
with everything we have.
The city will fall within a day.
If we turn the dragons loose,
tens of thousands will die
in the firestorms.
It's called war.
You don't have
the stomach for it,
scurry back into hiding.
I know how you wage war.
We don't poison
little girls here.
Myrcella was innocent.
She was a Lannister.
There are no
innocent Lannisters.
My greatest regret
is that Oberyn died
fighting for you.
Daenerys:
That's enough.
Lord Tyrion
is Hand of the Queen.
You will treat him with respect.
I am not here to be
queen of the ashes.
That's very nice to hear.
Of course,
I can't remember a queen
who was better loved
than my granddaughter.
The common people loved her.
The nobles loved her.
And what is left of her now?
Ashes.
Commoners, nobles,
they're all
just children, really.
They won't obey you
unless they fear you.
I'm grateful
to you, Lady Olenna,
for your counsel.
I'm grateful to all of you.
But you have chosen
to follow me.
I will not attack
King's Landing.
We will not attack
Then how do you mean
to take the Iron Throne?
By asking nicely?
We will lay siege
to the capital,
surrounding the city
on all sides.
Cersei will have
the Iron Throne,
but no food for her army
or the people.
But we won't use
Dothraki and Unsullied.
Cersei will try to rally
the lords of Westeros
by appealing to their loyalty,
their love for their country.
If we besiege the city
with foreigners,
we prove her point.
Our army should be Westerosi.
And I suppose
we're providing
the Westerosi?
You are.
Lady Greyjoy
will escort you home
to Sunspear.
And her Iron Fleet
will ferry the Dornish army
back up to King's Landing.
The Dornish
will lay siege
to the capital
alongside the Tyrell army.
Two great kingdoms
united against Cersei.
So, your master plan
is to use our armies.
Forgive me for asking,
but why did you bother
to bring your own?
The Unsullied will have
another objective.
For decades,
House Lannister has been
the true power in Westeros.
And the seat of that power
is Casterly Rock.
Grey Worm and the Unsullied
will sail for the Rock
and take it.
Do I have your support?
You have mine.
Dorne is with you, Your Grace.
Thank you all.
Lady Olenna, may I speak
with you alone?
I realize you're here
out of hatred for Cersei
and not love for me.
But I swear to you,
she will pay for
what she's done.
And we will bring peace
back to Westeros.
Peace?
Do you think
that's what we had
under your father?
Or his father?
Or his?
Peace never lasts, my dear.
Will you take
a bit of advice
from an old woman?
He's a clever man, your Hand.
I've known
a great many clever men.
I've outlived them all.
You know why?
I ignored them.
The lords of Westeros are sheep.
Are you a sheep?
No.
You're a dragon.
Be a dragon.
Grey Worm: Mají.
You leave tomorrow.
Were you going to say goodbye?
I will see you when I return.
But you don't know
when that will be.
No one knows.
I wish you good fortune.
Missandei.
It is hard for me
to say goodbye to you.
Why?
You know why.
I don't.
Y-you are my weakness.
That's what I am?
Your weakness?
When Unsullied are young,
the masters learn their fears.
One boy is scared of dogs,
one boy hates high places,
one is frightened of the ocean.
They make the boy
sleep with dogs
or climb a cliff.
They throw him in the water.
If he learns to swim, good.
If he drowns, good.
Either way, strong Unsullied.
But I had no fears.
I was never the biggest,
never the strongest...
but I was bravest, always.
- I believe it.
- Until...
I meet Missandei
from the Isle of Naath.
Now I have fear.
I do, too.
No.
I want to see you.
Please.
Might be useful.
Ch'Vyalthan was
a dreadful writer,
but an excellent researcher.
- Archmaester,
I wondered if I...
- And this one.
Maester Faull was
quite the opposite...
A brilliant stylist who
invented half the stories
he tells.
Um, I wanted
to ask you...
If you're going
to write histories, Tarly,
you have to do the research.
If you want people
to read your histories,
you need a bit of style.
I'm not writing
"A Chronicle of the Wars.
Following the Death
of King Robert I"
so it can sit on a shelf unread.
What?
You don't
like the title?
What would you call it, then?
Mm, possibly something
a bit more poetic?
We're not poets, Tarly.
Um, Archmaester,
if I could just
have a moment.
This is your moment.
Use it wisely.
I may have found a way
to treat Ser Jorah.
There are two recorded cases
of advanced greyscale
being cured.
I found the procedure
in the study of rare diseases
by Archmaester Pylos.
I'm familiar with
Archmaester Pylos
and his study of rare diseases.
- Oh, you are?
- Yes.
And shall I tell you
how he died?
From greyscale.
- Oh.
- The procedure's
far too dangerous,
which is why it's now forbidden.
Hello.
What are you doing?
You're Jorah Mormont,
the only son of Jeor Mormont.
My name is Samwell Tarly,
Sworn Brother
of the Night's Watch,
training to serve
as maester at Castle Black.
I knew your father.
I was with him when he died.
You are not
dying today,
Ser Jorah.
Drink this.
- What is it?
- Rum.
Drink it all, please.
I'm afraid this is
going to hurt.
If you could
take off your shirt.
If you wouldn't mind,
bite down hard.
I'm sorry, but no one
knows I'm here,
and if they
hear you screaming,
then we're both finished.
Jorah:
Have you ever
done this before?
No.
But no one else will try it,
so I'm the best you've got.
Have a seat.
I'm going to have to remove
the entire upper layer
of infected tissue,
then apply a medicinal
ointment to the...
Shh, shh!
Shh.
Again, I'm sorry,
but please try not to scream.
They say her dragons
are bigger than Aegon's.
Horseshit.
Cersei's just trying
to frighten us.
I hope it's true.
If she lays siege
to King's Landing,
prices will triple.
As long
as we get back there
before they start.
One more round.
It's a long ride.
Hot Pie:
Arry!
Hello, Hot Pie.
Sit down.
Who's that for?
Mm. This is good.
You think so?
The secret
is browning the butter
before making the dough.
Most people don't do that
'cause it takes up
too much time.
Mm, I didn't do that.
You've been making pies?
One or two.
I can't believe you're here.
Did you meet the big lady?
- Big lady?
- The lady knight?
You know,
I figured she was a knight
'cause she had armor on.
She was looking
for your sister,
but I told her about you.
Did she ever find you?
She found me.
What happened to you, Arry?
You got any ale?
- Where you heading?
- King's Landing.
- Why?
- Heard Cersei's
queen now.
Heard she blew up
the Great Sept.
That must have been
something to see.
- Boom.
- Mm.
I can't believe
someone would do that.
Cersei would do that.
I thought you'd be
heading for Winterfell.
Why would I go there?
The Boltons have it.
No, the Boltons are dead.
What?
Jon Snow came down
from Castle Black
with a wildling army
and won the Battle
of the Bastards.
He's King of the North now.
You're lying.
Why would I lie about that?
He's your brother, right?
Thanks for the pie.
Friends don't pay.
Can't believe
I thought you were a boy.
You're pretty.
Thanks.
Take care of yourself, Hot Pie.
Try not to get killed.
Ah, I won't.
I'm like you, Arry.
I'm a survivor.
200 miles to King's Landing.
One bottle of rum.
You think we'll make it?
Come in.
A raven, my king,
from the Citadel.
Jon:
This message was sent
to me by Samwell Tarly.
He was my brother
at the Night's Watch,
a man I trust as much
as anyone in this world.
He's discovered proof
that Dragonstone
sits on a mountain
of dragonglass.
I received this a few days ago
from Dragonstone.
It was sent to me
by Tyrion Lannister.
He is now
Hand of the Queen
to Daenerys Targaryen.
She intends to
take the Iron Throne
from Cersei Lannister.
She has a powerful army
at her back
and, if this message
is to be believed,
three dragons.
Jon: Lord Tyrion
has invited me
to Dragonstone
to meet with Daenerys.
And I'm going to accept.
Man: Accept?!
We need
this dragonglass,
my lords!
We know
that dragonglass
can destroy
both white walkers
and their army.
We need to mine it
and turn it into weapons.
But more importantly,
we need allies!
The Night King's army
grows larger by the day.
We can't defeat them on our own.
We don't have the numbers.
Daenerys has her own army
and she has dragonfire.
I need to try
and persuade her
to fight with us.
Ser Davos and I will ride
for White Harbor tomorrow,
then sail for Dragonstone.
Have you forgotten
what happened to
our grandfather?
The Mad King invited him
to King's Landing
- and roasted him alive.
- I know that.
She is here to
reclaim the Iron Throne
and the Seven Kingdoms.
The North is one
of those seven kingdoms.
This isn't an invitation;
it's a trap.
It could be,
but I don't believe
Tyrion would do that.
You know him.
He's a good man.
Your Grace, with respect,
I must agree with Lady Sansa.
I remember the Mad King
all too well.
A Targaryen cannot be trusted.
- Nor can a Lannister.
- All: Yeah!
Aye. We called
your brother king.
And then he rode south
and lost his kingdom.
Winter is here, Your Grace.
We need
the King in the North
in the North.
Men: Aye!
You all crowned me your king.
I never wanted it.
I never asked for it.
But I accepted it
because the North
is my home.
It's part of me,
and I will never
stop fighting for it,
no matter the odds.
But the odds are against us.
None of you have seen
the Army of the Dead.
None of you.
We can never hope
to defeat them alone.
We need allies, powerful allies.
I know it's a risk.
But I have to take it.
Then send an emissary.
Don't go yourself.
Daenerys is a queen.
Only a king can
convince her to help us.
It has to be me.
You're abandoning your people!
You're abandoning your home.
I'm leaving both in good hands.
- Whose?
- Yours.
You are my sister.
You're the only Stark
in Winterfell.
Until I return,
the North is yours.
Littlefinger:
I delivered his bones myself.
Presented them to Lady Catelyn
as a gesture of goodwill
from Tyrion Lannister.
Seems like a lifetime ago.
Do give Lord Tyrion my best
when you see him.
I was sorry when he died.
Your father and I
had our differences,
but he loved Cat very much.
So did I.
She wasn't fond of you, was she?
Well, it appears she vastly
underestimated you.
Your father
and brothers are gone,
yet here you stand,
King in the North.
Last best hope
against the coming storm.
You don't belong down here.
Forgive me.
We haven't ever
talked... properly.
I wanted to remedy that.
I have nothing to say to you.
Not even "thank you"?
If it weren't for me,
you'd have been slaughtered
on that battlefield.
You have many enemies,
my king, but I swear to you,
I'm not one of them.
I love Sansa,
as I loved her mother.
Touch my sister,
and I'll kill you myself.
- Man: Ready?
- Man #2: Ready?
Man #2:
Ready!
Come on.
- Man: Yah!
- Man #2: Come on!
Nymeria?
Nymeria, it's me, Arya.
I'm heading north, girl.
Back to Winterfell.
I'm finally going home.
Come with me.
That's not you.
Nym:
You can't have them all.
It's not fair.
Obara:
I'm oldest.
Mama will want Cersei
for herself.
She's not my mama.
You can have Cersei.
I want the Mountain.
The Mountain killed Father.
He'll crush you with one hand.
Father got careless.
That's what Mama says.
Will you shut up about Mama?
"Mama, Mama, Mama."
Maybe I'll kill you both
before we take King's Landing.
And then I won't have to share.
Both:
"Mama!"
How can you drink this piss?
When we reach Sunspear,
I'll treat you to a Dornish red.
The best in the world.
Have you ever been to Dorne?
A few times.
Never stayed long.
A boy in every port?
A boy, a girl.
Depends on the port.
Could we get some more?
I thought it wasn't for you.
I'm developing a taste for it.
- He's not your servant.
- It's fine.
So, you're going to be
Queen of the Iron Islands.
Once I kill my uncle.
And what will you be, handsome?
Whatever my queen commands.
He'll be my advisor,
my protector.
Oh, I see.
Your protector.
So, if someone gets
too close to you...
He might have to intervene.
To hold that person back.
Until they've made
their intentions known.
Why are you standing
all the way over there, then?
A foreign invasion is underway.
Leave him be.
Seems like you
don't need a protector.
Stay here.
Man: We're under attack!
Euron.
You mother's below deck.
Keep her safe.
Aah!
Yah!
Kill us.
Get it over with.
Give your uncle a kiss.
Euron:
Little Theon!
Ah, come on,
you cockless coward.
I have her.
Come and get her.
I was born
to rule the Seven Kingdoms.
And I will.
♪
The war's already begun.
I've drawn first blood.
Cersei will be ready.
They know we're coming.
♪
www.tvsubtitles.net