The stallion who mounts the world has no need for iron chairs.
According to the prophecy...
...the stallion will ride to the ends of the earth.
The earth ends at the black salt sea.
No horse can cross the poison water.
The earth does not end at the sea...
...there are many dirts beyond the sea.
The dirts of my birth. [[The dirt where l was born.]]
Not dirts. Lands.
Lands, yes...
There are thousands of ships in the free cities.
Wooden horses that fly across the sea...
Let's speak no more of wooden horses and iron chairs.
lt's not a chair. It's a...
A chair for a King to sit upon,
Or...
...a Queen.
A khal does not need a chair to sit upon.
He only needs a steed.
Sweet reds. I have it. I have it.
Sweet reds...
l have sweet reds from Lys, Volantis and the Arbor!
Tyroshi pear brandy! Andalish sours!
l have them! l have them!
A taste for the Khaleesi?
l have a sweet red from Dorne, my lady.
One taste and you'll name your first child after me.
Put down that cask.
Moon of my life.
Are you hurt?
Jorah the Andal,
l heard what you did.
Choose any horse you wish, it is yours.
l make this gift to you for what you did.
And to my son, the stallion who will mount the world,
l will also pledge a gift.
l will give him the iron chair...
...that his mother's father sat upon.
I will give The Lands of the Andals. [[l will give him Seven Kingdoms.]]
l, Drogo, will do this.
l will take my Khalasar west to where the world ends...
...and ride wooden horses across the black salt water...
- ...as no Khal has done before.
l will kill the men in iron suits...
- ...and tear down their stone houses.
- l will rape their women...
...take their children as slaves...
...and bring their broken gods back to Vaes Dothrak.
This, l vow...
...l, Drogo, son of Bharbo.
l swear before the Mother of Mountains...
...as the stars look down in witness.
As the stars look down in witness.
www.tvsubtitles.net