♪ Game of Thrones 1x02 ♪
The Kingsroad
Original Air Date on April 24, 2011
== sync,corrected by elderman ==
You need to drink, child.
And eat.
Isn't there
anything else?
The Dothraki have two things
in abundance:
Grass and horses.
People can't live on grass.
In the Shadow Lands
beyond Asshai,
they say there are
fields of ghost grass
with stalks as pale as milk
that glow in the night.
It murders
all other grass.
The Dothraki believe
that one day
it will cover everything--
that's the way the world will end.
It'll get easier.
Khaleesi!
Your hands.
We're still not far
from Pentos, your Grace.
Magister Illyrio has
extended his hospitality.
You'd be more
comfortable there.
I have no interest
in hospitality or comfort.
I'll stay with Drogo
until he fulfills
his end of the bargain
and I have my crown.
As you wish, your Grace.
Well, Mormont,
as brutish as this life is,
I suppose it is preferable
to beheading.
What did Ned Stark
want you for?
Buying from a slaver?
Selling to one--
some poachers I caught
on my land.
Under my reign, you won't be
punished for such nonsense.
You can rest assured
of that.
Better-looking bitches
than you're used to, Uncle.
My mother's been
looking for you.
We ride for
King's Landing today.
Before you go, you will call
on Lord and Lady Stark
and offer
your sympathies.
What good will
my sympathies do them?
None. But it is
expected of you.
Your absence has
already been noted.
The boy means
nothing to me.
And I can't stand
the wailing of women.
One word and I'll
hit you again.
I'm telling mother!
Go!
Tell her.
But first you will get
to Lord and Lady Stark
and you will fall on your knees
in front of them
and tell them how very sorry you are,
that you are at their service,
and that all your prayers are with them.
Do you understand?
You can't--
The prince will
remember that, little lord.
I hope so.
If he forgets, be a good dog
and remind him.
Ah.
Time for breakfast.
Bread.
And two of those little fish.
And a mug of dark beer
to wash it down.
And bacon,
burned black.
Hyah.
- Little brother.
- Beloved siblings.
Is Bran going to die?
Apparently not.
- What do you mean?
- The Maester says the boy may live.
It's no mercy, letting a child
linger in such pain.
Only the gods
know for certain.
All the rest of us
can do is pray.
The charms of the north
seem entirely lost on you.
I still can't believe
you're going.
It's ridiculous
even for you.
Where's your sense
of wonder?
The greatest structure ever built,
the intrepid men of The Night's Watch,
the wintry abode
of the White Walkers.
Tell me you're not thinking
of taking the black.
And go celibate?
The whores would go begging
from Dorne to Casterly Rock.
No, I just want to stand
on top of the wall
and piss off
the edge of the world.
The children don't need
to hear your filth.
Come.
Even if the boy lives,
he'll be a cripple, a grotesque.
Give me a good
clean death any day.
Speaking for the grotesques,
I'd have to disagree.
Death is so final,
whereas life...
Ah, life is full
of possibilities.
I hope the boy does wake.
I'd be very interested
to hear what he has to say.
My dear brother,
there are times you make me
wonder whose side you're on.
My dear brother,
you wound me.
You know how much
I love my family.
Please.
Oh, I would have
dressed, your Grace.
This is your home.
I'm your guest.
Handsome one, isn't he?
I lost my first boy,
a little black-haired beauty.
He was a fighter too--
tried to beat the fever
that took him.
Forgive me.
It's the last thing you
need to hear right now.
I never knew.
It was years ago.
Robert was crazed, beat
his hands bloody on the wall,
all the things men do to show
you how much they care.
The boy looked
just like him.
Such a little thing...
A bird without feathers.
They came to take his body away
and Robert held me.
I screamed and I battled,
but he held me.
That little bundle.
They took him away
and I never saw him again.
Never have visited
the crypt, never.
I pray to the mother
every morning and night
that she return
your child to you.
I am grateful.
Perhaps this time
she'll listen.
A sword for the wall?
- I already have one.
- Good man.
- Have you swung it yet?
- Of course I have.
At someone, I mean.
It's a strange thing,
the first time you cut a man.
You realize we're nothing
but sacks of meat
and blood and some bone
to keep it all standing.
Let me thank you
ahead of time
for guarding us all from
the perils beyond the wall--
Wildlings and White Walkers
and whatnot.
We're grateful to have
good, strong men like you
protecting us.
We've guarded the kingdoms
for 8,000 years.
Is it "we" already?
Have you taken
your vows then?
Soon enough.
Give my regards
to The Night's Watch.
I'm sure it will be thrilling
to serve in such an elite force.
And if not?
It's only for life.
Thank you, Nymeria.
Septa Mordane says
I have to do it again.
My things weren't
properly folded, she says.
Who cares how they're folded?!
They're going to get all
messed up anyway.
It's good
you've got help.
Watch.
Nymeria, gloves.
- Impressive.
- Shut up.
Nymeria, gloves!
I have something for you.
And it has to be packed
very carefully.
A present?
Close the door.
This is no toy.
Be careful you don't
cut yourself.
- It's so skinny.
- So are you.
I had the blacksmith
make it for you special.
It won't hack
a man's head off,
but it can poke him full
of holes if you're quick enough.
I can be quick.
You'll have to work
at it every day.
How does it feel?
Do you like
the balance?
I think so.
First lesson: Stick them
with the pointy end.
I know which end to use.
I'm going to miss you.
Careful.
All the best swords
have names, you know.
Sansa can keep
her sewing needles.
I've got a needle
of my own.
I came to say
goodbye to Bran.
You've said it.
I wish I could be here
when you wake up.
I'm going north
with Uncle Benjen.
I'm taking the black.
I know we always talked about
seeing the wall together,
but you'll be able to come visit me
at Castle Black when you're better.
I'll know my way
around by then.
I'll be a sworn brother
of The Night's Watch.
We can go out walking beyond the wall,
if you're not afraid.
I want you
to leave.
17 years ago
you rode off
with Robert Baratheon.
You came back a year later with
another woman's son.
And now
you're leaving again.
I have no choice.
That's what men always say
when honor calls.
That's what you tell your families,
tell yourselves.
You do have a choice.
And you've made it.
Cat--
I can't do it, Ned.
- I really can't.
- You can.
You must.
You've said
goodbye to Bran?
He's not going to die.
I know it.
You Starks
are hard to kill.
My mother?
- She was very kind.
- Good.
Next time I see you,
you'll be all in black.
It was always my color.
- Farewell, Snow.
- And you, Stark.
There's great honor serving
in The Night's Watch.
The Starks have manned the wall
for thousands of years.
And you are a Stark.
You might not have my name,
but you have my blood.
Is my mother alive?
Does she know about me?
Where I am, where I'm going?
Does she care?
The next time
we see each other,
we'll talk
about your mother.
Huh?
I promise.
Gods, this is country!
I've half a mind to leave them
all behind and keep going.
I've half a mind
to go with you.
What do you say,
just you and me
on the Kingsroad,
swords at our sides,
a couple of tavern wenches
to warm our beds tonight.
You should have
asked me 20 years ago.
There were wars to fight,
women to marry--
we never had the chance
to be young.
I recall
a few chances.
There was that one...
Oh, what was her name?
That common girl of yours?
Becca? With the great big tits
you could bury your face in.
Bessie.
She was one of yours.
Bessie!
Thank the gods for Bessie
and her tits.
Yours was... Aleena?
No. You told me once.
Meryl?
Your bastard's mother?
- Wylla.
- That's it.
She must have been
a rare wench
to make Lord Eddard Stark
forget his honor.
You never told me
what she looked like.
Nor will I.
We were at war.
None of us knew if we were
gonna go back home again.
You're too hard on yourself.
You always have been.
I swear if I weren't your King,
you'd have hit me already.
The worst thing
about your coronation--
I'll never get
to hit you again.
Trust me, that's not
the worst thing.
There was a rider
in the night.
Daenerys Targaryen has wed
some Dothraki horselord.
What of it?
Should we send her a wedding gift?
A knife perhaps,
a good sharp one,
and a bold man to wield it.
She's little more
than a child.
Soon enough that child will spread
her legs and start breeding.
- Tell me we're not speaking of this.
- Oh, it's unspeakable to you?
What her father did to your family--
that was unspeakable.
What Rhaegar Targaryen
did to your sister--
the woman I loved.
I'll kill every Targaryen
I get my hands on.
But you can't get
your hands on this one, can you?
This Khal Drogo,
it's said he has 100,000 men
in his horde.
Even a million Dothraki
are no threat to the realm,
as long as they remain on the
other side of the Narrow Sea.
They have no ships,
Robert.
There are still those in the
Seven Kingdoms who call me usurper.
If the Targaryen boy crosses
with a Dothraki horde at his back,
- the scum will join him.
- He will not cross.
And if by chance he does,
we'll throw him back into the sea.
There's a war coming, Ned.
I don't know when,
I don't know who
we'll be fighting,
but it's coming.
Sit.
You'll be fed.
Untie them.
Ah, rapers.
They were given a choice no doubt--
castration or the wall.
Most choose the knife.
Not impressed
by your new brothers?
Lovely thing
about the watch--
you discard your old family
and get a whole new one.
Why do you read so much?
Look at me and tell me
what you see.
Is this a trick?
What you see is a dwarf.
If I'd been born a peasant they might've
left me out in the woods to die.
Alas, I was born a Lannister
of Casterly Rock.
Things are expected of me.
My father was the Hand
of the King for 20 years.
Until your brother
killed that King.
Yes, until my brother
killed him.
Life is full of these
little ironies.
My sister married
the new King
and my repulsive nephew
will be King after him.
I must do my part for the honor
of my house, wouldn't you agree?
But how?
Well, my brother
has his sword
and I have my mind.
And a mind needs books
like a sword needs a whetstone.
That's why I read
so much, Jon Snow.
And you?
What's your story,
bastard?
Ask me nicely and maybe
I'll tell you, dwarf.
A bastard boy
with nothing to inherit,
off to join
the ancient order
of The Night's Watch,
alongside his Valiant
brothers-in-arms.
The Night's Watch protects
the realm from--
ah, yes yes, against grumpkins
and snarks
and all the other monsters
your wet nurse warned you about.
You're a smart boy.
You don't believe
that nonsense.
Everything's better
with some wine in the belly.
It's time we reviewed
the accounts, my lady.
You'll want to know how much
this royal visit has cost us.
Talk to Poole about it.
Poole went south
with Lord Stark, my lady.
We need a new steward,
and there are several other
appointments that require
- our immediate attention--
- I don't care about appointments!
I'll make the appointments.
We'll talk about it
first thing in the morning.
Very good, my Lord.
My Lady.
When was the last time
you left this room?
I have to take care
of him.
He's not going
to die, mother.
Maester Luwin says the most
dangerous time has passed.
What if he's wrong?
- Bran needs me.
- Rickon needs you.
He's six.
He doesn't know what's happening.
He follows me around all day,
- clutching my leg, crying--
- close the windows!
I can't stand it!
Please make them stop!
Fire.
You stay here.
I'll come back.
You're not supposed
to be here.
No one is
supposed to be here.
It's a mercy.
He's dead already.
No!
- Have you ever seen a dragon?
- Dragon gone, Khaleesi.
Everywhere?
Even in the east?
No dragon.
Brave men kill them.
- It is known.
A trader from Garth told me
that dragons come from the moon.
The moon?
He told me the moon
was an egg, Khaleesi,
that once there were
two moons in the sky.
But one wandered too close
to the sun and it cracked from the heat.
Out of it poured a thousand
thousand dragons
and they drank
the sun's fire.
Moon is no egg.
Moon is goddess--
wife of sun.
- It is known.
Leave me with her.
Why did the trader from Garth
tell you these stories?
Men like to talk
when they're happy.
Before your brother
bought me for you,
it was my job
to make men happy.
- How old were you?
- I was nine
when my mother sold me
to the pleasure house.
Nine?!
I did not touch a man
for three years, Khaleesi.
First
you must learn.
Can you teach me how
to make the Khal happy?
- Yes.
- Will it take three years?
No.
Welcome.
What I am about to tell
you must remain between us.
I don't think Bran
fell from that tower.
I think he was thrown.
The boy was always
sure-footed before.
Someone tried
to kill him twice.
Why?
Why murder an innocent child?
Unless he saw something
he wasn't meant to see.
- Saw what, my lady?
- I don't know.
But I would stake my life
the Lannisters are involved.
We already have reason
to suspect their loyalty to the crown.
Did you notice the dagger
the killer used?
It's too fine a weapon
for such a man.
The blade is Valyrian steel,
the handle dragonbone.
Someone gave it to him.
They come into our home
and try to murder my brother?
If it's war they want--
If it comes to that, you know
I'll stand behind you.
What, is there going to be
a battle in the Godswood?
Huh?
Too easily words of war
become acts of war.
We don't know
the truth yet.
Lord Stark
must be told of this.
I don't trust a raven
to carry these words.
- I'll ride to King's Landing.
- No.
There must always be
a Stark in Winterfell.
- I will go myself.
- Mother, you can't.
I must.
I'll send hal with a squad
of guardsmen to escort you.
Too large a party attracts
unwanted attention.
I don't want the Lannisters
to know I'm coming.
Let me accompany you
at least.
The Kingsroad can be a
dangerous place for a woman alone.
What about Bran?
I have prayed to the seven
for more than a month.
Bran's life is
in their hands now.
No, Khaleesi.
You must look
in his eyes always.
Love comes in at the eyes.
It is said that Irogenia of Lys
could finish a man
with nothing
but her eyes.
Finish a man?
Oh.
Kings traveled across
the world for a night with Irogenia.
Magisters sold
their palaces.
Khals burned her enemies
just to have her for a few hours.
They say a thousand men
proposed to her
and she refused them all.
Well, she sounds like
an interesting woman.
I-- I don't think
that Drogo will like it
with me on top.
You will make him
like it, Khaleesi.
Men want what
they've never had.
And the Dothraki take slaves
like a hound takes a bitch.
Are you a slave,
Khaleesi?
Then don't make love
like a slave.
Very good, Khaleesi.
Out there
he is the mighty Khal,
but in this tent,
he belongs to you.
I-- I don't think
that this is
the Dothraki way.
If he wanted
the Dothraki way,
why did he marry you?
No.
No!
Ajjalan anha zalat
vitiherat yer hatif.
Pardon me, Ser.
Do I frighten you
so much, girl?
Or is it him there
making you shake?
He frightens
me too.
Look at
that face.
I'm sorry
if I offended you, Ser.
Why won't he speak to me?
He hasn't been very talkative
these last 20 years.
Since the mad King had his tongue
ripped out with hot pincers.
He speaks damn well
with his sword though.
Ser Ilyn Payne,
the King's justice.
The royal
executioner.
What is it, sweet lady?
Does the hound frighten you?
Away with you, dog.
You're scaring
my lady.
I don't like
to see you upset.
The Sun is finally shining.
Come walk with me.
Stay, lady.
I probably shouldn't
have any more.
Father only lets us
have one cup at feasts.
My princess can drink
as much as she wants.
Don't worry--
you're safe with me.
I'll get you!
- Arya!
- Ow!
What are you doing here?
- Go away.
- Your sister?
- And who are you, boy?
- Mycah, my Lord.
- He the butcher's boy.
- He's my friend.
A butcher's boy who wants
to be a Knight, eh?
Pick up your sword, butcher's boy.
Let's see how good you are.
She asked me to, my Lord.
She asked me to.
I'm your prince,
not your lord,
and I said pick up
your sword.
It's not a sword, my prince.
It's only a stick.
And you're not a Knight.
Only a butcher's boy.
That was my lady's sister
you were hitting, do you know that?
- Stop it!
- Arya, stay out of this.
I won't hurt him...
Much.
Arya!
Filthy little bitch!
No no, stop it, stop it,
both of you.
You're spoiling it.
You're spoiling everything!
I'll gut you,
you little cunt!
- Arya!
- Nymeria!
No.
Please don't.
Arya, leave him alone.
My prince, my poor prince,
look what they did to you.
Stay here, I'll go back
to the inn and bring help.
Then go!
Don't touch me.
The wolf's not here.
Look down by the stream.
You've got to go. They'll kill you for
what you did to Joffrey.
Go on-- run.
Go!
Leave now!
- It's a direwolf.
- I'll check down here.
I think I heard a noise.
Go!
Arya!
- Distant man: Arya!
- Ned: Arya!
Arya-aa!
Arya!
My lord!
They found her.
She's unharmed.
Where is she?
She's been taken
directly before the King.
- Who took her?
- The Lannisters found her.
- Arya-aa!
- Right, get back.
The Queen ordered
them to bring her straight to him.
Back!
Back to the inn.
All back!
I'm sorry, I'm sorry,
I'm sorry.
- Are you hurt?
- No.
Oh, it's all right.
What is
the meaning of this?
Why was my daughter
not brought to me at once?
How dare you speak
to your King in that manner?
Quiet, woman.
Sorry, Ned.
I never meant to frighten the girl.
But we need to get
this business done quickly.
Your girl and that butcher's boy
attacked my son.
That animal of hers
nearly tore his arm off.
That's not true!
She just...
Bit him a little.
- He was hurting Mycah.
- Joff told us what happened.
You and that boy
beat him with clubs
- while you set your wolf on him.
- That's not what happened!
Yes it is!
They all attacked me and she
threw my sword in the river.
- Liar!
- Shut up!
Enough!
He tells me one thing,
she tells me another.
Seven hells!
What am I to make of this?
Where's your
other daughter, Ned?
In bed asleep.
She's not.
Sansa, come here, darling.
Now, child...
Tell me what happened.
Tell it all
and tell it true.
It's a great crime
to lie to a King.
I don't know.
I don't remember.
Everything happened so fast.
- I didn't see.
- Liar!
- Liar liar liar!
- Arya!
- Hey, stop it! That's enough of that.
- Liar liar liar!
- Stop! Arya!
- She's as wild as that animal of hers.
I want her punished.
What would you have me do,
whip her through the streets?
Damn it, children fight.
It's over.
Joffrey will bear these scars
for the rest of his life.
You let that
little girl disarm you?
Ned, see to it that
your daughter is disciplined.
- I'll do the same with my son.
- Gladly, your Grace.
And what of the direwolf?
What of the beast
that savaged your son?
I'd forgot
the damned wolf.
We found no trace
of the direwolf, your Grace.
No?
So be it.
We have another wolf.
As you will.
- You can't mean it.
- A direwolf's no pet.
Get her a dog.
She'll be happier for it.
He doesn't mean Lady,
does he?
No no, not lady!
Lady didn't bite anyone!
- She's good!
- Lady wasn't there!
- You leave her alone!
- Stop them. Don't let them do it.
Please please,
it wasn't Lady!
Is this your command--
your Grace?
- Where is the beast?
- Chained up outside, your Grace.
Ser Ilyn,
do me the honor.
No.
Jory...
Take the girls
to their rooms.
If it must be done,
then I'll do it myself.
Is this some trick?
The wolf is of the north.
She deserves better
than a butcher.
The butcher's boy--
you rode him down?
He ran...
Not very fast.
== sync,corrected by elderman ==
www.tvsubtitles.net