Uploaded by SOMNATH YADAV
[♪♪♪]
- Uploaded by SOMNATH YADAV -
-- download GOT https://infoontechworld.blogspot.com/p/tv-series.html -
[WIND WHISTLING]
[SAMWELL SHIVERING]
NORTHMAN 1: Oi!
NORTHMAN 2: Mind out.
Move!
[♪♪♪]
[MEN CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY]
NORTHMAN:
Look, on the west wall!
SOLDIER:
Get down to the crypt!
[BABY CRYING]
SOLDIER:
Just hold.
MAN:
We'll take him.
- Come on, help the lads!
SOLDIER 1: Yes, my lady.
LYANNA: Quickly, now! Quickly!
Get those in position.
SOLDIER 1: Come on.
SOLDIER 2: Close the gate!
SOLDIER 3:
That's it.
[♪♪♪]
[GRUNTS]
[WIND WHISTLING]
[EXHALES HEAVILY]
[GASPS SOFTLY]
[DRAGON ROARING]
[SOLDIERS SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY]
[HORSES SNORTING]
[CLEARS THROAT]
Oh, for fuck's sake.
You took your time.
[HORSE NEIGHS]
[SNORTING]
[WIND WHISTLING]
[DRAGONS GROWLING]
[♪♪♪]
Do you speak their tongue?
Tell them to lift their swords.
[WIND WHISTLING]
[SPEAKS IN DOTHRAKI]
[WEAPONS CLINKING]
[♪♪♪]
[SPEAKING IN HIGH VALYRIAN]
[SOLDIERS EXCLAIMING]
[♪♪♪]
Valar morghulis.
Valar dohaeris.
Open the gate!
SOLDIER 1:
SOLDIER 2:
Open the gate!
MAN 1:
Come. Come on.
Easy.
[♪♪♪]
There's no need to execute me,
Ser Davos.
I'll be dead before the dawn.
[♪♪♪]
[SOLDIER SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY]
[DOTHRAKI ULULATING]
SOLDIER [IN DOTHRAKI]:
[WIND WHISTLING]
[HOOFBEATS POUNDING]
[NEIGHS HOARSELY]
[♪♪♪]
[HORSES NEIGHING]
[GASPS]
The Night King is coming.
The dead are already here.
[DRAGON ROARS]
[♪♪♪]
[WIND WHISTLING]
[GREY WORM SPEAKS
IN VALYRIAN]
[UNSULLIED GRUNT]
[SOLDIERS GRUNTING]
[WIGHTS SNARLING]
[YELLS]
Stand your ground!
[SOLDIERS CLAMORING]
[SCREAMS]
[GRUNTS]
[♪♪♪]
[WIND WHISTLING]
ARYA:
Get down to the crypt.
SANSA:
I'm not abandoning my people.
ARYA:
Take this and go.
I don't know how to use it.
Stick them with the pointy end.
[♪♪♪]
[SOLDIERS GRUNTING]
[SOLDIER SHOUTS INDISTINCTLY]
SAMWELL:
Edd!
[WHIMPERING]
EDD:
Sam, get up!
[GASPING]
Oh, God. Sam.
[SNARLS]
WOMAN [SCREAMS]:
Edd!
[DOOR CLOSES, THEN LOCKS]
[PEOPLE WHISPERING
INDISTINCTLY]
[WIND WHISTLING]
[JON GRUNTS]
[DAENERYS GRUNTS]
[♪♪♪]
Fall back! Fall back!
Fall back!
SOLDIER:
Come on!
Open the gate!
SOLDIER 1:
SOLDIER 2:
Let us in!
SOLDIER 1:
Open the gate!
SOLDIER 3:
SOLDIER 4:
Keep moving!
SOLDIER 5:
Come on!
LYANNA: Keep moving, fast.
SOLDIER 5: To your posts.
SOLDIER 6: Go!
SOLDIER 7: Keep moving!
SOLDIER 1:
Come on, run!
Keep moving!
[IN VALYRIAN]
[UNSULLIED GRUNT]
[SOLDIERS CLAMORING]
[♪♪♪]
Dany!
[WIND WHISTLING]
SOLDIER 1:
Grab your weapon now!
SOLDIER 2:
Guard the barricades!
SOLDIER 3:
Through that pass!
BRIENNE:
Hey! Hey! Hey!
SOLDIER 4:
Close up the gaps!
Go! Hey! Go! Go!
Get in! Get in!
Get in! Come on!
[GREY WORM SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY]
[UNSULLIED GRUNTING]
[♪♪♪]
SOLDIER 1:
Move!
[SNARLING]
[SOLDIER WHIMPERING]
SOLDIER 1 [IN VALYRIAN]:
SOLDIER 2 [IN VALYRIAN]:
SOLDIER 1 [IN ENGLISH]: Come on!
SOLDIER 2 [IN ENGLISH]: Come on!
SOLDIER 1: Come on!
SOLDIER 3: Come on!
LYANNA:
Protect the gate!
SOLDIER 1:
They're coming! Come on!
Fall back!
[PANTING]
Light the trench!
SOLDIER 2: Wait!
SOLDIER 3: Light the trench!
[GRUNTS]
[♪♪♪]
She can't see us.
Light the trenches!
SOLDIER 1: With a torch,
light the trenches!
- Right there.
SOLDIER 2: Torch it!
Light the trenches!
[GRUNTING]
[SNARLING]
[SHOUTS INDISTINCTLY]
[SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[UNSULLIED GRUNT]
[MAN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[SPEAKS IN VALYRIAN]
[UNSULLIED GRUNT]
[SPEAKING IN HIGH VALYRIAN]
[♪♪♪]
[SCREECHING]
[SOLDIERS SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY]
Clegane.
[BABY CRYING]
WOMAN [SOFTLY]: You must try
not to worry yourself.
[SIGHS] At least we're already
in a crypt.
If we were up there,
we might see something
everyone else is missing.
Something that makes
a difference.
- [SCOFFS]
- What?
Remember the Battle
of Blackwater?
I brought us
through the Mud Gate.
And got your face cut in half.
And it made a difference.
If I was out there right now...
You'd die.
There's nothing you can do.
You might be surprised
at the lengths I'd go
to avoid joining
the Army of the Dead.
I could think of no organization
less suited to my talents.
Witty remarks
won't make a difference.
That's why we're down here,
none of us can do anything.
It's the truth.
It's the most heroic thing
we can do now...
look the truth in the face.
Maybe we should have
stayed married.
You were the best of them.
What a terrifying thought.
It wouldn't work between us.
Why not?
The Dragon Queen.
Your divided loyalties
would become a problem.
MISSANDEI:
Yes.
Without the Dragon Queen,
there'd be no problem at all.
We'd all be dead already.
[WIND WHISTLING]
They lit the trench.
Bran...
I just want you to know...
I wish...
The things I did...
Everything you did
brought you where you are now.
Where you belong.
Home.
I'm going to go now.
Go where?
[♪♪♪]
[RAVENS CAWING]
Man the walls!
SOLDIER 1:
SOLDIER 2:
Man the wall!
Man the walls!
Come on!
Get out there! Get moving!
Come on. Come on! Come on!
Go, go, go!
BRIENNE:
Come on!
[ROARS]
SOLDIER 1:
They're against the wall!
Get more men up here!
- Fill the gaps, quickly!
- Get in there!
SOLDIER 2:
They're climbing the walls!
- Relieve the archers!
SOLDIER 2: Relieve the archers!
Archers on top!
SOLDIER 1: Move up!
SOLDIER 2: Go, go! Come here!
- Come on!
SOLDIER 3: Move back!
SOLDIER 4: Stand away!
SOLDIER 2: Go on, go on. Go! Go.
SOLDIER 3: Step back.
SOLDIER 4: All the way, archers!
[SPEAKS IN VALYRIAN]
[SNARLING]
SOLDIER 1:
Hold the wall!
SOLDIER 2:
The wall, they're coming up!
SOLDIER 3: Hold the wall!
SOLDIER 4: Hold the wall!
Draw!
Come on!
[♪♪♪]
[YELLS]
SOLDIER:
They're coming up!
Look out!
[WHIMPERING]
[SHUDDERING]
[♪♪♪]
[YELLS]
[GRUNTING]
Clegane!
[SCREAMS]
[GRUNTS]
BERIC:
Clegane!
Clegane, we need you!
You can't give up on us.
Fuck off! We can't beat them.
Don't you see that,
you stupid whore?
We're fighting Death!
They can't beat Death.
Tell her that.
[PANTING]
[SCREAMING]
[GASPING]
[YELLS]
[ROARS]
[♪♪♪]
[DAENERYS WHIMPERING]
[GRUNTING]
[♪♪♪]
[PANTING]
[FOOTSTEPS]
[♪♪♪]
[WIGHT CROAKS]
[SNARLING]
[GASPS SOFTLY]
[WIND WHISTLING]
[SNARLING IN DISTANCE]
[BREATHING SHAKILY]
[SNARLING]
[PANTING]
[WIGHTS SNARLING IN DISTANCE]
[MEN YELLING IN DISTANCE]
[DOOR THUDS]
[ALL GASPING]
SOLDIER 1:
Open the door!
SOLDIER 2:
SOLDIER 3: Come on!
SOLDIER 4: Open the door!
Open the door!
Please!
Open it!
[SOLDIERS SCREAMING
INDISTINCTLY]
[SCREAMING FADES]
[WIND WHISTLING]
[OBJECT CLATTERS
IN DISTANCE]
- [OBJECT THUDS]
- [GASPS]
[WIGHTS SNARLING
IN DISTANCE]
[SCREAMING]
Rah!
Aah!
[GRUNTING]
Come on! Go!
- Come on!
BERIC: Run!
We've gotta go!
[♪♪♪]
[PANTING]
[SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
MELISANDRE: The Lord brought him back
for a purpose.
Now that purpose
has been served.
[♪♪♪]
I know you.
And I know you.
You said we'd meet again.
And here we are.
At the end of the world.
You said I'd shut
many eyes forever.
You were right about that too.
Brown eyes...
green eyes...
and blue eyes.
[WIGHTS SNARLING
AND THUDDING ON DOOR]
What do we say
to the God of Death?
Not today.
[♪♪♪]
[WIND WHISTLING]
[WIGHTS SNARLING]
[GASPS SOFTLY]
Here they come!
Steady, lads.
Steady now.
Make every shot count.
[♪♪♪]
MAN 1:
Over there!
MAN 2:
There!
[♪♪♪]
JON:
Get off.
[GRUNTING]
[JON GRUNTS]
[GROANS]
[PANTING]
[ROARS]
[DRAGON ROARING]
[♪♪♪]
Dracarys.
[DAENERYS GRUNTS]
[♪♪♪]
[PANTING]
[WIND WHISTLING]
[ALL GRUNTING]
[♪♪♪]
[JON YELLS]
[WIGHTS RUSTLING]
[GASPS]
[SNARLING]
[BABY CRYING]
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
Come on! Come on!
No! No, no, no!
[GRUNTING]
[♪♪♪]
- Bran!
DAENERYS: Go!
[WIGHTS SNARLING]
[DROGON ROARING]
[DROGON SCREECHES]
[GRUNTS]
[WHIMPERS]
[♪♪♪]
[YELLING INDISTINCTLY]
[GRUNTS]
[SAMWELL SCREAMING]
[HISSING AND SNARLING]
[YELLS]
[SCREAMING]
[PANTING]
[♪♪♪]
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
[DRAGON ROARS]
[GRUNTS]
Jorah!
[ROARING]
[GRUNTS]
[YELLS]
[SNIFFLING]
[GASPS]
BRAN:
Theon.
You're a good man.
Thank you.
[YELLING]
[GRUNTING]
[GRUNTS]
[VISERION ROARS]
[YELLS]
[GRUNTS]
[GASPS]
[♪♪♪]
I'm hurt.
[SOBBING]
[GROWLING SOFTLY]
[♪♪♪]
(FIRE CRACKLING)
♪ (DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYS) ♪
DAENERYS TARGARYEN:
We have won the Great War.
Now, we will win the last war.
(CHEERING)
♪ (MUSIC INTENSIFIES) ♪
DAENERYS: We'll rip her out
root and stem.
- (WHIMPERS)
- MAN: Mind out!
Move.
We've been building
towards this for so long now.
You think back
to the very beginning
of the very first episode,
and it's beyond the Wall where
the White Walkers are stalking.
They're a group of rangers.
So, this is the culmination of
one of the key storylines
in... in the whole show.
And this is for everything.
We've been talking for
a long time,
how Night King's forces
have been growing in power,
and most of the living
have been kind of
openly disdainful of the threat,
and now there's no choice
but to fight it.
♪ (DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
DAVID BENIOFF:
I really love the way
the first ten minutes or so
plays out,
because there's so much tension
before there's any encounter
with the enemy.
BOY: Come on!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
BENIOFF: You know, as much as
they try to conceal it,
people are terrified,
because this is...
this is death coming for them.
You know, so much of it is just
kind of, on one hand,
setting the mood
for the episode,
and the other hand, showing us where
these characters are gonna be.
The entire episode takes place
in Winterfell.
And you have 19 or 20 characters
all involved
in a very chaotic situation,
that needs many, many locations
to service it.
BENIOFF: Because it's such
a long battle in this episode,
it's important that we feel
the ebb and flow.
And so, there are moments
when you think things
are going a little bit better
for the living.
Tell them to lift their swords.
We felt like it was important
to have that moment of hope,
when Mel comes in and lights up
their arakh,
and they all ride off
into battle.
(SPEAKS VALYRIAN)
(SOLDIERS GASP)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
D.B. WEISS: We wanted
our characters to feel, like,
that this... maybe this is
all gonna work out,
maybe things are all gonna
be okay.
We've seen how devastating a Dothraki charge
can be just with their regular swords,
and now when they're galloping
into combat
with, uh, flaming arakhs,
it's... it's...
Uh... What could possibly
stand against that?
(HORSE WHINNIES)
BENIOFF:
What they see is just
the end of the Dothraki,
essentially.
WEISS: They have a plan,
and it's important
to wait for the Night King
to reveal himself,
and then have two dragons
against one dragon,
and a really good chance
of... of defeating him.
One thing that
they couldn't have foreseen
was Daeny's reaction to seeing
the Dothraki decimated.
Jon is the person who
wants to stick to the plan,
but the Dothraki are not Jon's;
they're not loyal to Jon,
they're loyal to Daeny,
and I think that Daeny can't bring
herself to just watch them die,
and so the plan starts
to fall apart
the second she gets
on her dragon,
so he does too,
and then we take it from there.
♪ (TENSE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(SNARLING)
BENIOFF: We knew this episode was
gonna be almost entirely battle,
and that can get really boring
really quickly.
You can watch it
for a certain number of minutes
before the effect starts
to dampen.
Part of it was making sure that we
really stayed focused on the characters,
and so whether it's Arya's
storyline,
or Sansa and Tyrion
down the crypt,
or Jon Snow and Daeny
up on the dragons.
Kinda like all these separate
little battles within the...
within the greater battle.
- (SWORDS CLANKING)
- (SNARLING)
Lyanna Mormont was supposed
to be a one-scene character,
and then we met
Bella Ramsay,
and we realized that we would
not be doing our jobs
if we kept her as
a one-scene character.
My mother wasn't a great beauty
or any other kind of beauty.
She was a great warrior, though.
She died fighting
for your brother, Robb.
WEISS: We knew that
you can't give a...
a big death to everybody
who dies in this battle,
'cause it would've...
It just would've been too much,
but there...
Also, if she were to die,
there was no way to... to not
make a moment of it, so...
that's where the zombie giant
comes in.
It just did add a whole level
of complexity
to that moment,
that I'm sure a lot of people
would've been okay with
not having there,
if we had demanded to cut it,
but I think they also
understood why we needed
to give one of the strongest
smaller people in the show
a chance to go out
taking down
one of the strongest
larger things we've, uh,
we've ever seen in the show.
- (LYANNA SCREAMS)
- (ZOMBIE GIANT GROWLS)
(ARYA SHRIEKS)
WEISS: In any situation
where people are fighting,
Arya needs to play
a central role,
'cause she's one of
the best at it,
and she's one of the most fun
to watch doing it.
- (ARYA GRUNTS)
- BENIOFF: Even for Arya,
she can't take on a horde
of wights by herself,
and especially when her head
gets smacked,
she's no longer at 100 percent.
It's just about survival
at that point.
WEISS: Otherwise,
she's completely unstoppable,
and she never loses her cool,
and it's amazing, and it's
a lot of fun to watch,
but it's also... it's one note,
so we decided that almost rewinding
the clock on who Arya Stark is
to back before she became this sort
of magical figure that she's become
would really be interesting,
and would also give us a chance
to change up
the nature of the story
we were telling.
We talked about Winterfell as
kind of the home for the show,
and, uh, one of the things
that always struck us
as a horrific aspect of this
is that these hallways
and rooms where we spent
a lot of good times
and... and quiet times with
characters that we care about,
has now become a horror set,
because it's been invaded by
undead soldiers.
(SNARLS)
WEISS: Before that point,
there's sort of an agoraphobia
to the whole thing
where you have
this giant wide-open space
and everywhere you look
you... there's something
that could be coming
to kill you.
Once you get inside Winterfell,
everything contracts,
and the... the walls literally
start to close in around you,
and something is there
in the dark with you,
but you don't know exactly
where it is.
And we thought that
the pace change
and the tonal change
was really important
to have that in this episode,
otherwise the episode
would start to feel...
would start to feel monotonous.
Dracarys.
WEISS: We thought it was
important that,
whatever the plan was,
that it not just work out,
'cause that would be
kind of dull.
While there's no reason to know
for certain that
the fire wouldn't kill
or destroy the Night King,
there's also no particular
reason to believe that it would.
And then, a few moments after
this happens,
the Night King brings them
a whole new,
larger undead problem
by taking all of their own
who have been killed
in the course of this battle,
and turning them into the enemy.
BENIOFF: I mean, we talked about
various endings for Jorah
for a long time, but, you know,
you think about Jorah,
from the very first time
we met him, he was with Daeny,
and from that time,
he's been mostly by her side.
Part of Jorah's tragedy is
that he was in love with a woman
who couldn't love him back,
but he's accepted that
for quite a long time,
at the same time he was
going to fight for her
as long as he could
and as well as he could.
There'd never been a moment
where she more needed someone
to fight to protect her
than this moment.
And if he could've chosen
a way to die,
this is how he would've chosen
to die.
So, it was something we thought
would be powerful to give him.
- (DAENERYS SOBS)
- (DRAGON EXHALES)
BENIOFF: The reason
the Godswood was chosen
is because it's such
a source of power
for those who believe in the old
gods, and for Bran in particular,
so we know the weirwood tree
and the three-eyed raven
have a very deep connection.
That was always the location
where Bran was going
to be waiting
for the Night King.
I just want you to know...
- the things I did...
- Everything you did
brought you where you are now.
Where you belong.
Home.
WEISS: It's not like the show
is entirely about
people redeeming themselves
and then it's all over,
but if you... if the canvas
is big enough,
there are spaces for those
redemptive moments.
I think what was
really important for Theon
at the end was hearing
that thank you from Bran,
because Bran knows
what's gonna happen.
BRAN: Theon.
You're a good man.
Thank you.
He knows he's dead,
he knows he's not gonna be able
to kill the Night King,
but I think what's really heroic
about his action is that
we're all gonna die,
and we know we're not gonna be
able to defeat death at the end,
but, you know, it's... it's how
you face those final moments,
and he chooses to run
straight at it,
and I think he dies in a way
that, um, makes us
really proud of him and
the journey he's gone through.
- (ARYA SCREAMS)
- BENIOFF: For...
God, I think it's probably
three years now or something,
we've known that it was
gonna be Arya
who delivers that...
that fatal blow.
WEISS: She seemed like
the best candidate,
provided we weren't thinking
about her in that moment.
One of the great things
about having this many people
you care about
in a sequence together
is that it can kind of
pull people's attention
and focus to people that
they care about a lot,
like Jon, like Daeny,
Theon, and Bran,
not to mention Tyrion
and Sansa in the crypt,
so you're going
all over the place
with people who you're
desperately worried for,
and, uh, hopefully
you forget about the fact that
Arya Stark ran out of
that castle
with the battle drums playing,
going towards some purpose,
and we don't know what
until it happens.
BENIOFF: We hoped to kind of
avoid the expected,
and Jon Snow has
always been the hero,
the one who's been the savior,
but it just didn't seem right
to us, for this...
for this moment.
We knew it had to be Valyrian
steel, to the exact spot where
the child of the forest put the dragonglass
blade to create the Night King,
and he is uncreated
by the Valyrian steel.
At the end of it, it's still...
It's a victory for the living,
but at great cost,
because some of our favorite
characters fall along the way.
WEISS: We knew from
the beginning,
once we'd handed the outline in,
what we were in for.
The director, Miguel Sapochnik,
took what we were doing
and defined this episode.
Miguel did
a tremendous amount of
heroic heavy lifting
on this front.
He knew that if the planning
wasn't there,
we never would've ended up
with the consistent excellence
that he delivered.
It is to their immense credit
that...
not only that they endured it,
um,
but that they did such a great job
the whole time they were there.
WEISS: It's a real testament
to the entire Belfast crew
who gave us something that no
amount of money could ever buy.
www.tvsubtitles.net