What was she like?
She...
she had red hair.
Oh?
- How big were her feet?
- What do you want me to say?
I want you to tell me what
it was like to have someone.
To be with someone.
To love someone and have
them love you back.
We're all gonna die a lot
sooner than I'd planned.
You're the closest
I'll ever get to knowing.
So you and Gilly never?
No.
She just had a baby.
And she never offered.
But if she had,
you would have?
You'd have broken
your vows?
The interesting
thing is,
our vows never
specifically forbid
intimate relations
with women.
What?
"I shall take no wife," yes, that's
in there. There's no denying that.
"I shall father no children."
It's very specific.
But what do our vows
have to say about other...
activities is open
to interpretation.
I don't think Ser Alliser
cares much for interpretation.
Anyway, there's nothing
for him to interpret.
We didn't.
So what's it like?
It's...
there's this person,
this whole other person.
And you're wrapped up in them
and they're wrapped up in you.
And you--
for a little--
for a little while,
you're more than just you.
You're-- I don't know.
I'm not a bleeding poet.
No, you're really not.
What did I get for it?
An arrow six inches
from my heart.
There'll be arrows for all
of us soon, I imagine.
There will.
They've already done the worst
thing to me they could ever do.
Go get some sleep, Sam.
I'll take this watch.
Did I ever
tell you about her?
- My Sheila?
- Yes.
That was a night
to remember.
Of course, I'd had
a good bit to drink.
Her fangs were sharp,
but she knew
how to use them.
And she was nice
and soft down below.
No, she was no
ordinary beast.
Many is the man who--
I know you never
fucked a bear.
You know you never
Right now I don't want to think
about the bear you never fucked.
Right now all I want
to think about
is each one of these arrows finding
its way into a crow's heart.
We could be waiting
here a while.
Good.
The longer we wait,
the more arrows I'll have.
They came up here
to our land
and put up a big wall
and said it was theirs.
Then they started
hunting us down.
This time, we're the ones
doing the hunting.
You've got a lot
to say about killing.
Even more words
than arrows.
Back in those villages, I killed
just as many of them as you did.
More, I reckon.
Yes, but none of those
were your crow lover.
I probably killed
him already.
So you've said.
And if not,
the only thing left of him is gonna be
his fun bits hanging around my neck.
More words.
Know what I think
you do when you see him?
Serve him up a nice juicy
slice of ginger minge.
You been thinking
about that ginger minge?
Wondering what
it tastes like?
Maybe I have.
Jon Snow is mine.
Anyone else
tries to kill him,
I'll have
an arrow for them.
And not one of your bald friends
is fast enough to stop me.
And what is it that couldn't
wait until morning, Tarly?
Maester Aemon.
- How did you know--
- That it was you?
Who else
but Samwell Tarly
would be wasting candles
to read in the middle
of the night?
- Let me help you.
- Oh, no need.
I know my way
around this library
better than any other
place in Castle Black.
Thousands of books
and no eyes to read them.
Old age is a wonderful
source of ironies
if nothing else.
But you didn't
answer my question.
What are you reading?
Maester Faull.
Ah, the wildlings.
I can assure you that
the closest Maester Faull
ever got to a wildling
was this very library.
But what he says
about what they do,
it's all true.
It's exactly what the survivors
of their raids report.
Yes, imagine the stories
wildlings tell about us.
Love is the death
of duty.
I told that to your friend
Jon Snow once.
He didn't listen
and neither did you.
Which is why you've abandoned
your watch atop the Wall
to come here and read
about the terrible things
that may have happened
to the girl you love.
I don't love her.
- Yes, you do.
- No.
Yes, you do.
Heard it in your voice when
you first brought her to me.
I remember how it sounds.
I was in love once.
You were?
You can imagine
all manner of horrors
befalling that poor
girl and her child.
Is it so difficult
to imagine
that an old person
was once,
more or less,
like you?
I'm sorry, Maester.
I didn't mean it
like that.
Do you know who I was
before I came here?
What I could have been
if I'd only said the word?
Of course you do.
I met many girls
when I was Aemon Targaryen.
A future king
always does.
Some of them
were quite forward
in their attempts
to win my affections.
One of them succeeded.
I was very young.
Who was she?
Ah.
I could tell you
everything about her.
Who she was,
how we met,
the color of her eyes,
and the shape
of her nose.
I can see her
right in front of me.
She's more real
than you are.
We could spend all night
trading tales of lost loves.
Nothing makes the past
a sweeter place to visit
than the prospect
of imminent death.
Go to bed, Tarly.
Sorry, I can't open the gate
for anybody. Orders.
- You don't understand.
- They killed everyone.
Everyone but me
and my baby.
They're out there.
I saw them on my way here.
They may have seen me. They
may have followed me. Please.
I'm sorry, I can't.
If they find us out here,
you don't know...
Pyp!
Open the gate.
- I can't.
- Sam, is that you?
Yes.
Thorne gave me strict
orders to not open the gate.
Oh, Pyp,
open the fucking gate!
I never heard you
curse before.
Yes, well,
best get used to it.
Are you all right?
Shh, you're all right.
Of course you are,
my brave little fella.
- It was horrible.
- I'm so, so sorry.
I didn't know
until I got back.
Don't let them
send me away, Sam.
- Never. - I know there's
no women allowed.
Anyone who tries to throw you out
will be having words with me.
From now on,
wherever you go,
I go, too.
Get ready!
- Man the gate!
- Ready yourselves!
Make haste!
- Prepare!
- Up on the Wall!
Quickly!
Up! Up!
-  How many?
- How many are there?
Beyond the trees!
It's time.
Light them up!
Light them all!
Move!
Pick up the pace!
Come on, come on.
Here we go, boys,
there's one.
Let's go.
There's two.
Let's get the next load.
That's the last
of the oil, Ser Alliser.
100,000 you say?
Yes, Ser.
You can say it
if you like.
We should have sealed the
tunnel while we had the chance,
like you suggested.
It was a difficult
decision either way, Ser.
Do you know what leadership
means, Lord Snow?
It means that the person in
charge gets second-guessed
by every clever little
twat with a mouth.
But if he starts
second-guessing himself,
that's the end--
for him, for the
clever little twats,
for everyone.
This is not the end.
Not for us.
Not if you lot
do your duty
for however long it takes
to beat them back.
And then you get
to go on hating me
and I get
to go on wishing
your wildling whore
had finished the job.
You'll be safe
down here.
I'll check on you
as soon as I can.
You're leaving me again?
I'm not leaving you.
You're going up there and we're
staying down here. That's leaving.
You said from now on
we'd stay together.
I didn't mean
in the same room.
What are you going
to do out there?
- Help my brothers.
- How?
You're going to fight the
free folk when they come?
They'll kill you. In Mole's
Town, they killed everyone.
I can't just hide here with you
while they're fighting out there.
Why not? You won't
matter up there.
You will down here.
I am a man of
the Night's Watch, Gilly.
I made a promise
to defend the Wall
and I have to keep it
because that's
what men do.
Promise me
you won't die.
I promise you
I won't die.
There's a lot more wildlings on the
other side of the Wall than this side.
We've got loads
of weapons and things.
It's the perfect place
for us to be.
I've never thrown
a spear before.
I've never held a sword
with a proper edge.
This is no place
for me to be.
You're not afraid?
Of course I'm afraid.
There's a band of wildlings
coming to kill us.
If you're afraid
of a band of wildlings,
how in seven hells did you
manage to kill a white walker?
I didn't know
I was going to kill it.
But I had to do something.
I didn't have any choice.
It was going to kill Gilly
and take the baby.
If someone had asked
me my name right then,
I wouldn't have known.
I wasn't
Samwell Tarly anymore.
I wasn't a steward
in the Night's Watch
or son of Randyll Tarly
or any of that.
I was nothing at all.
And when you're
nothing at all,
there's no more reason
to be afraid.
But you're afraid now?
Yes, well...
I'm not nothing anymore.
Most of their men
are up top.
Didn't count more than 20 down here.
Leftovers.
They got a big fat one and a
little bony one manning the front.
How high are the walls?
Well, we'll be up and over before
they know what's happened.
Let's kill some crows!
Come on!
Come on, brothers!
Archers nock.
Everyone else hold.
Grenn, no!
I said nock and hold,
you cunts!
- Does nock mean draw?
- No, Ser!
- Does fucking hold mean fucking drop?
- You all plan to die here tonight?
- No, Ser!
That's very good to hear.
Draw!
No, down below!
Light them up.
Come on, get up!
They're attacking
the southern gate!
- Now?
- Now.
I'm going down there. Brother
Slynt, you have the Wall.
What?
What are you fucking waiting for?
Loose!
You heard the man.
You, over there.
- Did you get one?
- No.
Ah, shit, Pyp!
Shit.
- Sam.
- Yeah?
- I think
we're gonna die.
If you keep
missing, we will.
Come on!
Brothers!
100 generations
have defended this castle.
She's never fallen before.
She will not fall tonight.
Those are Thenns
at our walls.
They eat the flesh
of the men they kill.
Do you want to fill
the belly of a Thenn tonight?
No!
Tonight we fight.
And when the sun rises,
I promise you,
Castle Black will stand!
The Night's Watch
will stand.
With me now!
Now with me!
No discipline.
No training.
Gang of thieves,
that's all this is.
I commanded the City Watch
of King's Landing.
Those men obeyed orders.
We can't just let
them attack the gate!
The bars of those gates are four
inches of cold-rolled steel.
Those are giants riding
mammoths down there!
Do you think your cold-rolled
steel is gonna stop them?
No such thing
as giants.
A story
for the children.
Brother Slynt.
We just got word that Ser
Alliser needs you below.
You're the most experienced man
he's got, Ser, and he needs you.
Needed below?
Yes. Yes.
Archers, nock your arrows!
Nock arrows!
Draw!
Loose!
They won't summit
before dawn.
How do you know that?
Because I've made
that climb.
I think they're in a bigger
hurry than you were.
Hold the bridge!
Hold, wait for it!
Come on with the rocks!
Nock!
Draw!
Loose!
Down!
No! No!
To the gate.
Come on, let's move.
It's gonna open.
I got one right through the heart.
He's dead.
- Oh, is it over?
- No.
Well, then...
You're all right.
I'll get help.
Shh. Shh.
Maester Aemon is coming.
He's gonna make
it all right.
Shh. Shh.
- Now.
- Now!
The outer gate
won't hold.
Take five men,
hold the inner gate.
Aye.
Hold the gate.
If they make it through...
They won't.
Come on, Hill.
And you, Cooper.
- You three, on me.
Come on,
you lazy bastards.
Oil.
Oil on the ramp!
Protect the gate!
Get him inside.
Hold the fucking gate!
Hold it!
We need more men
down here.
- We have to hold the gate.
- But we need men here.
Tell Jon.
He's in command.
Let's go.
Get me to the top!
You hear me?!
Your name's Olly, right?
Listen to me, Olly.
Get me to the top.
And when we give the signal,
bring us back down.
You hear me?
Find a weapon, Olly.
Fight them.
Clear the way!
Let's go!
- Out of the way!
- Get out of here!
Cut the rope!
Wait! No!
- We need more archers.
- Here I am.
- Come on.
- Quickly.
What are you
doing up here?
The wildlings
are over the walls.
Ser Alliser's fallen.
The castle won't stand
much longer.
Edd, you have the Wall.
If they try the mammoths
again, drop fire on them.
If the climbers get too high,
drop the scythe on them.
Come, brothers.
Now fight with me!
Might as well enjoy
our last night, right, boys?
Light the fuckers up!
Nock! Draw!
Loose!
How are we
gonna stop that?
Shot 20 arrows
in him already.
You heard Jon.
We hold the gate.
Jon Snow's not
Lord Commander.
We hold the gate!
Mother, save me.
Father, save me.
The gods aren't down here.
It's the six of us.
You hear me?
Night gathers
and now my watch begins.
It shall not end
until my death.
I shall take no wife,
hold no lands,
father no children.
I shall wear no crown
and win no glory.
I shall live and die
at my post.
I am the sword
in the darkness.
I am the watcher
on the walls.
I am the shield that guards
the realms of men.
I pledge my life and honor
to the Night's Watch
for this night
and all the nights to come!
I don't want you
out there.
You can't
protect me forever.
There won't be anywhere
to hide if the castle falls.
I need him
more than I need you.
We need you, boy.
Ha!
Jon Snow.
Hush.
Don't talk.
Do you remember the cave?
We should have
stayed in the cave.
We'll go back there.
You know nothing,
Jon Snow.
Drop the scythe, boys!
- Hoist her up.
- Hoist her up!
They've had enough
for one night.
Don't cheer too loud.
They still outnumber us
1,000 to one.
Tormund.
It's over.
Let it end.
This is how a man ends.
Put him in chains.
We'll question him later.
I should have
thrown you
from the top
of the Wall, boy!
Aye.
You should have.
Whoa, it's me.
It's me.
I promised you,
didn't I?
We held them off.
For one night.
This is a great
victory.
A great victory?
Mance was testing
our defenses.
He almost
made it through.
And he has more giants.
He has more mammoths.
He has 1,000 times
as many men.
They'll hit us
again tonight.
Maybe we can hold them
off for a day or two,
but we'll never
beat them.
Where are we going?
Going to find Mance.
To fi---
you can't do that.
No one gave you
any orders.
Who's left
to give orders?
The wildling army's only
an army because of Mance.
He united
100 warring tribes.
Without Mance,
they lose their leader.
They lose their purpose. They
go back to fighting each other.
Scatter back
to their homes.
Without Mance?
You're going to kill him?
I'm gonna try.
They'll never let you
within 100 yards of him.
And even if they did, even
if you managed to kill him--
They'll kill me? If I don't
go, they'll kill me anyway.
They'll kill
the rest of us, too.
They won't just kill you.
They'll boil you.
They'll flay you.
They'll make it last days.
You're right.
It's a bad plan.
What's your plan?
They held the gate.
Get some brothers
down here to help you.
We need to burn
the bodies.
Raise the outer gate.
Then lower it again
as soon as I'm out.
What are you doing?
I promised Mormont
I'd never lose it again.
In case I don't come back.
Jon.
Come back.
www.tvsubtitles.net