- I lost this dagger.
- To whom?
Tyrion Lannister.
Take a step into a more productive relationship
with a possible ally.
I will allow you to mine the dragon glass
and forge weapons from it.
Thank you.
She has three full-grown dragons,
Your Grace.
How do you propose to stop them?
We are currently at work on a solution.
I thought you'd be headed to Winterfell?
Jon Snow came down from Castle Black and the wildling army
and won the Battle of the Bastards.
He's King of the North now.
Your sister's dead?
Euron has her.
I couldn't save her.
I tried.
You wouldn't be here if you tried.
What about Casterly Rock?
We both know how expensive war can be.
Your vaults are empty.
My debt will be paid in full.
How will it happen?
Will there be pain?
No, I made sure of that.
I'd hate to die like your son.
Not at all what I intended.
Tell Cersei,
I want her to know it was me.
[theme music playing]
« Sync & corrections by BoyKulet007 »
« of House Kyusi »
Hold the waggon!
You've just won the biggest prize in the world.
What could you possibly have to be upset about?
Come on, you can tell me.
The Queen of Thorns give you one
last prick in the balls before saying goodbye?
I will save my confessions
for the High Septon.
-There is no more High Septon.
-No there isn't, is there?
There is still the question of my prize.
That's a lot of money I just gave you.
It's not a castle.
How about that one?
It's available.
You don't want Highgarden.
-I beg to differ.
-We are at war.
Daenerys Targaryen can come and take it
back the day after you move in.
Besides, think of the upkeep.
The more you own,
the more it weighs you down.
Oh! Is that why you are so fucking glum,eh?
All your new riches weighing you down?
Move it!
They are not mine.
These all belong to the Iron Bank.
-We pay our debts.
-Right, just not to me.
Ser Bronn of the Blackwater, formerly of
whatever nameless shitheap you're from,
with a saddlebag full of gold,
complaining about not getting paid.
When we win this war, all the castles in the
Seven Kingdoms will be yours to choose from.
with no one left to take them away from you.
Yes, I am sure Queen Cersei's reign
will be quiet & peaceful
-Oh! Stranger things have happened.
-Like what?
The granaries are being emptied.
I'll load it into wagons, my lord.
And the current harvest?
We have teams of men collecting it
from all the farms in the Reach.
Ser Bronn, will you accompany the Tarlys
and help them accelerate this process?
I'm not much for shoveling wheat.
No. But, motivating reluctant farmers
to hand over their harvest,
I bet you're going to have
a real talent for that.
My Lord.
I must say I don't think the Iron Bank
has ever had a debt of this magnitude
repaid in a single installment.
I always considered your father
a very effective and efficient man,
but you appear to be
redefining those terms entirely.
You're too kind, my Lord.
I'm neither kind nor a lord, Your Grace.
I'm merely an instrument of
the institution I represent.
It's well-being is a matter
of arithmetic, not sentiment.
And the current arithmetic is outstanding.
-The gold...
-is on it's way.
My brother is supervising
its transportation himself.
Some at the Iron Bank
will be disappointed.
They've grown rather fond
of your interest payments.
We must devise a way to raise their spirits.
Yes, perhaps we could be of
assistance in some current venture.
My only venture at this moment is
re-estabilishing control over this continent
and every person on it.
I see a great deal of potential in that venture.
I imagine it will require outside investment.
It will, indeed.
I need to expand my armies, my navies.
My Hand, Qyburn,
has made overtures
to the Golden Company in Essos.
I know them well.
They have helped us recover significant sums
from parties who had fallen to deep arrears.
It's good to hear.
I too would like them to recover
some things that belong to me.
Rest assured, Your Grace...
You can count on the Iron Bank's support...
..as soon as the gold arrives.
This is for you.
The last man who wielded it
meant to cut your throat,
but your mother fought him off.
The other dagger,
the one that took her life.
I would have stopped
that dagger with my own heart
If I could have.
I wasn't there for her
when she needed me most.
But I am here for her now
to do what she would have done,
to protect her children.
anything I can do for you, Brandon,
you need only ask.
Do you know who this belonged to?
No.
That very question was what started
the war of the Five Kings.
In a way that dagger made
you what you are today.
Forced from your home,
driven out to the wilds beyond The Wall.
I imagine you've seen things
most men wouldn't believe.
To go through all of that and..
make your way home again
only to find such chaos in the world.
-I can only imagine.
-Chaos is a ladder.
I'm sorry to have disturbed you,
Lord Stark.
I'm not Lord Stark.
What's that?
Maester Wolkan built it for me
so I can move around more easily.
It's a very good idea.
You're leaving.
I don't want to leave you, but when...
..when they come,
I need to be with my family.
And you're safe.
Safe as anyone can be now.
You don't need me anymore.
No, I don't.
That's all you've got to say?
Thank you.
Thank you?
For helping me.
My brother died for you.
Hodor and Summer died for you.
I almost died for you.
-Bran...
-I'm not really...
Not anymore.
I remember what it felt
like to be Brandon Stark.
But I remember so much else now.
You died in that cave.
Yes! The kitchen girl...
the redhead with the band.
The only thing in the kitchen
that you put your ... is the liver.
Hello. Where are you goin'?
In there.
-I live here.
-Fuck off.
I am Arya Stark. This is my home.
[laughs]
Arya Stark is dead.
Send for Maester Luwin or Ser Rodrik.
-They will tell you who I am.
-There is no Rodrik here.
The Maester's name Wolkan.
Go ask Jon Snow then,
the King in the North.
-He's my brother.
-He's a thousand miles away.
It's cold and we're busy.
So, you know, better fuck off.
If Jon's gone,
who's in charge of Winterfell?
The Lady of Winterfell?
-Lady Stark.
-Which Lady Stark?
You tell us,
you are the one impersonating her sister.
Tell Sansa her sister's home.
Lady Sansa is too busy
to waste a breath on you.
Just like us.
So for the last time, FUCK OFF.
I'm getting into this castle
one way or another.
If I'm not who I say I am,
I won't last long.
But if am, and Sansa
finds out you turned me away...
All right. You sit there.
Right there.
Don't move!
Alright,
Go tell Lady Stark. I'll watch her.
I ain't telling Lady Stark. You go tell..
-You are going to tell her.
-I'm not.
Because if you don't I'm gonna hit you
right in the fucking face as hard as I can.
We told her to wait.
We were standing right next to her and...
When we turned around,
she was gone, milady.
She is nothing, some winter town girl.
-She comes in asking for Ser Rodrik... and
Maester Luwin, yeah. And...
Don't trouble yourself over her, milady.
We will find her.
You don't have to.
I know where she is.
Do I have to call you Lady Stark now?
Yes.
You shouldn't have run
from the guards.
I didn't run.
You need better guards.
It suits you... Lady Stark.
-Jon left you in charge?
-He did.
I hope he comes back soon.
I remember how happy he was to see me,
and when he sees you,
his heart will probably stop.
It doesn't look like him.
Should've been carved
by someone who knew his face.
Everyone who knew his face is dead.
We're not.
They say you killed Joffrey.
Did you?
I wish I had.
Hmmm.
Me too.
I was angry when I heard
someone else had done it.
However long my list go,
he was always first.
-Your list?
-Of people I'm going to kill.
[laughs]
How did you get back to Winterfell?
It's a long story.
I imagine yours is too.
Yes.
Not a very pleasant one.
Mine neither.
But our stories aren't over yet.
No, they're not.
Arya.
Bran is home too.
You came home.
I saw you at the crossroads.
-You saw me?
-I see quite a lot now.
Bran has visions.
I thought you might go to King's Landing.
So did I.
Why would you go back there?
Cersei's on her list of names.
Who else is on your list?
Most of them are dead already.
Where did you get this?
Littlefinger gave it to me.
Littlefinger? He's here?
He's declared for House Stark.
Why would he give you a dagger?
He thought I'd want it.
-Why?
-Because it was meant to kill me.
The cut-throat?
After your fall?
Why would a cut-throat
have a Valyrian steel dagger?
Someone very wealthy wanted me dead.
He's not a generous man.
He wouldn't give you anything unless
he thought he was getting something back.
-It doesn't matter.
-What do you mean "It doesn't matter"?
I don't want it.
Are you sure?
-It's Valyrian steel.
-It's wasted on a cripple.
Catelyn Stark would be proud.
You kept your vow.
-I did next to nothing.
-You're too hard on yourself, my lady.
I'm not a...!
Thank you, Podrick.
Your Grace, there is still
no word from the Unsullied.
Soon.
He will come back to you.
He better!
What happened?
Many things...
Many things?
Your Grace!
-
I wanted you to see it
before we start hacking it to bits.
Well, this is it..
All we'll ever need.
There is something else
I wanna show you, Your Grace.
The Children of the Forest made these.
When?
A very long time ago.
They were right here,
standing where we're standing.
Before there were Targaryens,
or Starks or Lannisters.
Maybe even before there were men.
No.
They were here together.
the Children and the First Men.
Doing what?
Fighting each other?
They fought together
against their common enemy.
Despite their differences,
despite their suspicions.
Together.
We need to do the same
if we are gonna survive.
Because the enemy is real.
It's always been real.
And you say can't defeat them
without my armies and my dragons.
No, I don't think I can.
I will fight for you.
I will fight for the North.
When you bend the knee.
My people
won't accept a southern ruler.
Not after everything they have suffered.
They will if their King does.
They chose you to lead them.
They chose you to protect them.
Isn't their survival more
important than your pride?
What is it?
We took Casterly Rock.
That's very good to hear.
Isn't it?
You'll want to discuss this amongst yourselves.
You will stay.
All my allies are gone.
-They've been taken from me
while I've been sitting here on this island.
-You still have the largest army.
...who won't be able to eat because
Cersei has taken all the food from the Reach.
Call Grey Worm and the Unsullied back.
We still have enough ships to carry
the Dothraki to the mainland.
Commit to the blockade of King's Landing.
We have a plan. It's still the right plan.
The right plan!
Your strategy has lost us
Dorne, the Iron Islands and the Reach.
-If I have underestimated our enemies--
-Our enemies?
Your family you mean!
Perhaps you don't want to
hurt them after all.
Enough of the clever plans.
I have three large dragons.
I am going to fly them to the Red Keep.
We've discussed this.
My enemies are in the Red Keep.
What kind of a Queen am I
if I am not willing to risk my life to fight them?
A smart one.
What do you think I should do?
-I would never presume--
-I'm at war.
I'm losing.
What do you think I should do?
I never thought that
dragons would exist again.
No one did.
The people who follow you
know that you made
something impossible happen.
Maybe that helps them believe that you
can make other impossible things happen.
Build a world that's different
from the shit one they've always known.
But if you use them to
melt castles and burn cities
You're not different.
You're just more of the same.
Don't lunge.
Don't go where your enemy leads you.
Up.
-And don't--
-Don't fight someone like her in the first place.
Nice sword.
Very nice dagger.
They haven't contributed the right
amount of grain to the stores
that I am afraid they'll have to make do
with what they brought. We can't--
It's been a while since I trained.
I can go and find the master-of-arms here,
my lady.
He didn't beat The Hound.
You did.
I want to train with you.
You swore to serve both my
mother's daughters, didn't you?
Move aside, Podrick.
You can't use that, my lady.
It's too small.
I won't cut you.
Don't worry.
I'll try not to.
Who taught you how to do that?
No one.
-What do you think of her?
-Who?
I believe you know of whom I speak.
I think she has a good heart.
A good heart?
I've noticed you staring at a good heart.
There's no time for that.
I saw the Night King, Davos.
I looked into his eyes.
How many men do we have
in the North to fight him?
-10,000 less?
-Fewer.
What?
Speaking of good hearts.
Missandei of Naath.
Ser Davos, Lord Snow.
King Snow, isn't it?
No, that doesn't sound right.
-King Jon?
-It doesn't matter.
Forgive me.
But may I ask a question?
Of course.
Your name is Jon Snow,
but your father's name was Ned Stark.
I'm a bastard.
My mother and father weren't married.
Is the custom different in Naath?
We don't have marriage in Naath,
so the concept of a bastard doesn't exist.
It sounds... liberating.
Why did you leave your homeland?
I was stolen away by slavers.
I'm sorry.
If I may,
how did a slave girl come
to advice Daenerys Targaryen?
She bought me from my master
and set me free.
That was good of her.
Of course you are serving her now,
aren't you?
I serve my Queen because
I want to serve my Queen.
Because I believe in her.
And if you wanted to sail
home to Naath tomorrow?
Then she would give me a ship
and wish me good fortune.
You believe that?
I know it.
All of us who came with her from Essos
We believe in her.
She's not our Queen because
she's the daughter of some king we never knew.
She is the Queen we chose.
Will you forgive me if I switch sides?
Is that a Greyjoy ship?
Stop!
Jon.
I didn't know you were here.
Sansa...
Is she alright?
What you did for her
is the only reason
I am not killing you.
We heard your
uncle attacked your fleet.
We thought you were dead.
I should be.
Your sister?
Euron has her.
I came to ask the Queen
to help me get her back.
The Queen is gone.
Where did she go?
-All the gold's safely through
the gates of King's Landing.
-Good.
We need to get the last of these wagons over
the Blackwater Rush before night fall.
If the head of the line is ambushed,
the tail will never be ought to reinforced in time.
We are stretched a bit thin.
With your permission,
flogging stragglers
has a marked effect on mobility.
Let's give them fair warning first.
These men fought well at High Garden.
-Sir Jaime.
-Rickon.
Dickon.
I hear you fought bravely at High Garden.
Your first battle?
And...?
It was glorious.
Come on, your father's not here.
All my life we've been placed at House Tyrell.
I knew some of those men, hunting with them.
They didn't deserve to die.
But Lady Olenna chose to betray her Queen
and supported Targaryen girl.
So here we are.
I didn't expect her to smell like that.
Men shit themselves when they die.
Didn't they teach you that at fancy lad school?
Well I learnt it when I was five.
What?
Listen.
Spears and shields!
-What is it?
-Get in line!
Spears and shields!
In line now!
Fall now!
Come on, lads!
Halt those wagons! Fall align!
Fall align!
Grab those spears!
Shield wall!
Fill the gaps!
In tight!
In line, boys!
[Dothraki shouting]
Spears out!
Hold the line!
Get back to King's Landing.
I'm not abandoning my army.
-You're the Commander, not a damned infantry man.
Those fuckers are about to swamp us.
We can hold them off.
Dracarys!
Hold the line!
Hold the line.
-Archers!
Archers, with me!
...to the line!
-Nock!
-Loose!
-Qyburn's Scorpion is over there.
-Go get it then.
I can't shoot with one hand.
Come on!
Where are you?
---
Take cover!
Come on, you fucker!
Dracarys!
Flee, you idiot.
Come on boy. Come on!
You fool.
You fucking idiot!
www.tvsubtitles.net