We're going to braavos!
In the old times,
whenever braavos
stood in danger,
The titan would step
with fire in his eyes.
He'd wade into the sea
and smash the enemies.
He's just a statue.
Don't be afraid.
He's announcing
our arrival.
I'm not afraid.
The house
of black and white.
This is where you'll find
the man you seek.
Here i leave you.
Thank you
for bringing me.
Any man of braavos
would have done the same.
Valar morghulis.
Valar dohaeris.
Hello.
Valar morghulis.
Um...
Jaqen h'ghar gave me this.
No one here
by that name.
Please.
I crossed the narrow sea.
I have nowhere else to go.
You have everywhere
else to go.
But wait--
Cersei.
Walder frey.
The mountain.
Meryn trant.
Cersei.
Walder frey.
The mountain.
Meryn trant.
cersei. Walder frey.
The mountain.
Meryn trant.
Cersei.
Walder frey.
The mountain.
Meryn trant.
Cersei.
Walder frey.
The mountain.
Meryn trant.
Must be good food
if it's crowded.
Ale?
Before we left, a maester
gave you a raven scroll.
You are becoming
an observant young lady.
My mother used to say,
"dark wings, dark words."
An old saying.
Inaccurate in this case.
Excuse me.
So it was good news?
My marriage proposal
has been accepted.
I thought you still mourned
the death of my beloved
aunt lysa.
Ale?
I'll have some.
My lady.
What is it?
Sansa stark.
Don't look.
You sure?
She's dyed her hair,
but it's her.
She's sitting
with petyr baelish.
Littlefinger?
A bunch of knights
with him.
A bunch?
What's a bunch, podrick?
Six? 20?
10, i think.
Too many.
My lady, i don't think
this is the right--
Ready the horses.
We only have one horse.
Find more.
Do you like the taste?
I don't see what
all the fuss is about.
Why do men
love it so much?
It gives some men courage.
Does it give you courage?
That's far enough.
Lord baelish,
lady sansa.
My name is brienne of tarth.
We've met
with renly baratheon.
What did he say about you?
He said, "your loyalty
came free of charge."
Someone appears
to have paid quite
a bit for it since then.
Lady sansa,
Before your mother's death,
I was her sworn sword.
I gave my word i would
find you and protect you.
I will shield your back
and keep your counsel
And give my life
for yours if need be.
I swear it
by the old gods
and the new.
Please, lady brienne,
No need
for such formality.
You were catelyn stark's
sworn sword?
I was.
Strange.
I knew cat from the time
we were children.
She never mentioned you.
It was after
renly's murder.
Ah, yes.
You were accused
of killing him.
I tried to save him.
But you were accused.
By men who didn't see
what happened.
And what did happen?
He was murdered
by a shadow.
A shadow with the face
of stannis baratheon.
A shadow?
With the face--
This woman swore
to protect renly.
She failed.
She swore
to protect your mother.
She failed.
Why would i want somebody
with your history of failure
guarding lady sansa?
Why should you have
any say in her affairs?
Because i am her uncle.
I married her aunt lysa
shortly before my beloved's
untimely death.
We're family now
and you are an outsider.
Forgive me, lady brienne,
but experience has made me
wary of outsiders.
Lady sansa, if we can
have a word alone--
No.
Please, my lady.
If i could explain--
I saw you at joffrey's
wedding bowing to the king.
Neither of us
wanted to be there.
Sometimes we don't
have a choice.
And sometimes we do.
You should leave.
We don't want
our new friend wandering
the countryside alone.
The roads in these parts
aren't safe.
Why don't you stay?
The man asked you
to stay--
hyah! Hyah!
Hyah! Hyah!
After her!
Yah! Hah!
Oh!
Stop! Stop!
I'll take him!
Podrick!
Guard #2:
Hold on to her!
Take her!
Guard #3:
Keep moving!
stop! Stop! Stop!
Stop! Stop!
That's a good boy.
Come on. Come on.
no, no, no, stop!
I guess that means
you're unarmed.
Down, podrick! Down!
Podrick.
Yes, my lady?
You can stand now.
Yes, my lady.
Sansa stark?
Wary of strangers,
as she should be.
I saw her riding
on the east road
with littlefinger.
We'll follow them.
My lady,
if both stark girls
refused your service,
Maybe you're released
from your vow.
I swore to their mother
i would protect those girls.
But if they don't want
your protection--
Do you think she's safe
with littlefinger?
No, my lady.
Get your horse.
A summons from the queen.
There are only two
like it in the world.
The one i'm wearing,
the one i gave to myrcella.
It's a threat.
Of course it's a threat.
Our daughter's
alone in dorne
Surrounded by people
who hate our family.
"it's a threat."
No note?
They blame us for the death
of oberyn and his sister
And every other tragedy
that's befallen their
cursed country.
I will burn
their cities to the ground
if they touch her.
Softer.
What?
Not so loud.
Our daughter's in danger
and you're worried i'm
speaking too loudly?
The world can't know
she's our daughter.
Then don't call her
your daughter.
You've never been
a father to her.
If i was a father to any
of my children, they'd be
stoned in the street.
And what has
your caution brought?
Our eldest child murdered
at his own wedding.
Our only daughter
shipped off to dorne.
Our baby boy set to marry
That smirking whore
from highgarden.
I'm going to make
things better.
You've never made
anything better.
I'm going to dorne
And i'm bringing
our daughter home.
you can't just
ask prince doran
To give her back.
She's promised to his son.
I'm not going
to ask him anything.
You go down
there with an army,
it's an act of war.
No army.
Do you know where
they're keeping her?
Oberyn mentioned
the water gardens.
I'll find her.
Is there anything else,
your grace?
you're going to dorne?
A one-handed man alone?
I never said
i was going alone.
No sunflowers.
I don't like yellow.
Roses are very nice.
Definitely roses.
And music.
I adore music.
But no flutes.
I hate flutes.
We can have
a harp if you like,
but no flutes.
Then there's the food.
Food is the most
important thing.
Don't you agree?
We're going to need
pigeon pies.
That's what they eat
in the capital,
don't they?
Don't they?
Don't who?
People eat
pigeon pie
in the capital.
They certainly do,
my dear.
They certainly do.
It's a fine place,
isn't it?
A fine place.
I never thought
i'd end up
Settling down
in a place like this.
You won't.
Pardon?
We won't get to live
at stokeworth.
When mother dies,
my sister gets the castle
because she's older.
Oh.
She hates me.
She calls me mean names
and sometimes even still
She pulls my hair
when mother's not looking.
You know what i think?
I think you're
a good person.
And your sister
is a mean person.
She is.
I've been all over
the world,
And if there's one thing
i've learned,
It's that meanness
comes around.
People like your sister,
They always get what's coming
to them eventually.
One way or another.
Who's that?
Jaime fucking lannister.
Ser jaime.
Ser bronn of the blackwater.
I was very sorry
to hear about your father.
Thank you.
This is
my betrothed lollys.
A pleasure.
Run along, love.
Beautiful young bride
you've chosen.
When were you planning
on getting married?
Just get on with it.
On with what?
What you're here for.
There's no way this little
visit could possibly mean
anything good for me.
It's very good for you.
Lollys will be marrying
ser willis bracken.
Mmm.
We made a deal,
your sister and i.
I would have
advised against that.
How is this good for me?
'cause you're going to come
with me and help me with
something important.
And when we return,
i'm going to give you
a much better girl
And a much better castle.
Return from where?
As far south
as south goes.
My future queen.
The prince does not wish
to be disturbed.
Remove yourself
from my path
Or i'll take that longaxe
and i'll shove it--
Captain.
Let her pass.
Your brother was murdered
And you sit here
in the water gardens
Staring at the sky
and doing nothing.
Oberyn was slain
during a trial by combat.
By law,
that is not murder.
Your brother.
You don't have
to remind me.
He was my brother long before
he was anything to you.
What will you do
about his death?
I will bury him.
I will mourn for him.
And then?
You would
have me go to war?
The whole country
would have you go to war.
Then we are lucky
the whole country
does not decide.
The sand snakes
are with me.
They have the love
of their people.
They will avenge
their father while
you sit here
In your chair
doing nothing.
Oberyn is dead
And this lannister girl skips
about the water gardens
Eating our food,
breathing our air.
How many of your
brothers and sisters
do they have to kill?
Let me have her.
Let me send her to cersei
one finger at a time.
I loved my brother.
And you made him
very happy.
For that, you will always
have a place in my heart.
But we do not
mutilate little girls
for vengeance.
Not here.
Not while i rule.
And how long
will that be?
The unsullied
are too conspicuous.
Anyone can see you coming
from a mile off.
Of course you haven't found
any sons of the harpy.
You haven't, have you?
My second sons,
on the other hand,
They drink,
they whore,
Fight in the streets,
They blend in.
They overhear
things in taverns,
Follow people
from the taverns
to nice, quiet alleys,
Break a few fingers,
Overhear
a few more things.
Before you know it...
No one here.
We go.
In a hurry?
You're afraid?
Unsullied fear nothing.
Right.
That's your problem.
You understood fear
once long ago,
But you've forgotten
what it means.
Someone who's
forgotten fear
Has forgotten how to hide.
Fear is useful
that way.
Sons of the harpy,
they want to put a collar
back on my neck.
On all of our necks.
Please, your grace,
you must kill him.
It would send a message.
I think you should
exercise restraint,
your grace.
Why?
For one thing, he may have
valuable information.
The son of the harpy
has no more valuable
information.
How do you know that?
Because i questioned him.
And the information
you did get,
He is young and poor.
He is born free.
Why should he want
to bring back slavery?
What did it do for him?
Perhaps the only thing
that gave him pride
Was knowing
that there was someone
lower than he was.
They pay him.
Great families
afraid to do a thing.
They pay poor man
to do it for them.
And how do you know this?
Everyone know this.
I don't know it
and i'm the head
of a great family.
We do not know what
this man did or didn't do.
Give him a trial at least.
A fair trial.
Show all the citizens
of meereen
That you're better than
those who would depose you.
Teach them a better way.
I do not know
the place from where
old ser comes.
Things maybe are
different there, i hope.
But here in meereen,
Before daenerys stormborn,
they own us.
So we learn
much about them
Or we do not live long.
They teach me
what they are.
Mercy, fair trial--
these mean nothing to them.
All they understand
is blood.
Thank you all
for your counsel.
Your grace,
a word, please,
i beg you.
About what?
About your father.
About the mad king.
The mad king?
You're here to remind me
of my enemies' lies?
Consider me reminded.
Your grace, i served
in his kingsguard.
I was at his side
from the first.
Your enemies did not lie.
Go on.
When the people rose
in revolt against him,
Your father set their towns
and castles aflame.
He murdered sons
in front of their fathers.
He burned men alive
with wildfire
And laughed
as they screamed.
And his efforts
to stamp out dissent
Led to rebellion
that killed every
targaryen except two.
I'm not my father.
No, your grace.
Thank the gods.
But the mad king gave
his enemies the justice
he thought they deserved.
And each time,
it made him feel
powerful and right.
Until the very end.
I will not have the son
of the harpy executed
Without a fair trial.
Your grace.
There's a bug.
Yes, best be careful.
You might accidently
consume some solid food.
When i agreed
to come with you,
Did i misrepresent
my intentions?
Besides, what else
is there for me to do
Inside this fucking box?
You don't like it?
I want to take a walk.
You can't.
Cersei has offered
a lordship
To the man
who brings her
your head.
She ought to offer
her cunt.
Best part of her
for the best part of me.
Well, i suppose a box
is as good a place
for me as anywhere.
Are we really going
to spend the entire
road to volantis
Talking about
the futility of everything?
You're right.
No point.
The road to volantis?
You said we were
going to meereen.
What's in volantis?
The road to meereen.
And what do you hope
to find at the end of
the road to meereen?
I told you.
A ruler.
We've already got
a ruler.
Everywhere has already
got a ruler.
Every pile of shit
on the side of every road
Has someone's banner
hanging from it.
You were quite good,
you know, at ruling.
During your brief
tenure as hand.
I didn't rule.
I was a servant.
Still, a man of talent.
Managed to kill
a lot of people.
Yes, but you showed
great promise in other
areas as well.
She wanted me
to leave king's landing.
She begged me.
I wouldn't go.
Why?
'cause i liked it.
Power.
Even as a servant.
People follow leaders.
And they will never
follow us.
They find us repulsive.
I find us repulsive.
And we find them repulsive,
Which is why we surround
ourselves with large,
comfortable boxes
To keep them away.
And yet,
No matter what we do,
People like you and me
are never really satisfied
inside the box.
Not for long.
You're right.
Let's go for a walk.
No.
How many dwarves
are there in the world?
Is cersei going
to kill them all?
Not him.
Are you trying
to deceive your queen?
Shall i throw them
in a cell, your grace?
That won't be necessary,
ser meryn.
I don't want to dissuade
the other hunters.
Mistakes will be made.
Thank you,
your grace, thank you.
Your grace, thank you.
Take the head.
Pardon me, your grace.
I would take it
if you don't mind.
It could prove useful
for my work.
Very good.
Over there
will be fine.
You heard the man.
Over there.
You're the hand
of the king?
No, uncle.
Clearly it would not
be appropriate
For a woman
to assume that role.
I'm merely advising my son
until he comes of age
And chooses a hand
for himself.
Your grace, i would
be willing to serve
provisionally
As the king's hand
until he becomes
old enough--
You're a good man,
lord tyrell,
But i don't imagine
you'll have the time.
In addition to being
master of ships,
The king
has appointed you
master of coin.
Oh, your grace.
He called your experience
and wisdom
In financial matters
unparalleled.
He said he would
be honored to have you
Represent the crown's
interests in the same.
The honor is all mine,
your grace.
Your grace, in the past
on several occasions,
A grand maester has served
as the king's hand.
The king has named qyburn
the new master of whisperers.
Your grace, him?
This-- this man?
This embarrassment
to the citadel?
Your grace,
what qualifications
Can he possibly have
for this post?
The qualification
of loyalty, grand maester.
That's far more
than the eunuch ever had.
Far more than many
ever have.
I must say,
i cannot see--
Uncle kevan, in light
of your position
As commander
of the lannister armies,
It would please the king
if you would serve as his
master of war.
No man living
better deserves
the title.
That is kind
of you to say.
I would like to hear it
from the king himself.
The king is very busy
at this moment.
He should be here
learning what it means
to rule.
He is learning.
On this occasion,
in his capacity as ruler,
He's asked me to speak
on his behalf.
I returned to the capital
to pay my respects
to my brother.
And to you.
And to serve the king.
I did not return
to the capital
To serve as your puppet.
To watch you stack
the small council
with sycophants.
Sending your own brother
away so he wouldn't be--
My brother has left
the capital to lead
A sensitive
diplomatic mission.
What mission?
That is not your concern
as master of war.
I do not recognize
your authority
To dictate what is
and is not my concern.
You are the queen mother,
nothing more.
You would abandon your king
in his time of need?
If he wants to send for me,
i will be waiting for him.
At casterly rock.
Come on, you know
this one.
It looks like
an animal.
Snake.
Sssnake. S.
It's an s.
Right, very good.
Huh!
Did you know that the youngest
lord commander in history
Osric stark was elected
at the age of 10?
I know s.
You'll learn,
i promise.
I taught ser davos,
and old people are terrible
at learning new things.
Well, you're
a wonderful teacher.
Very patient.
I only said
that the more time
that you spend practicing,
The faster
you'll be able to read.
That's all right.
We're doing just fine.
I'm sure you
and "ostrich" stark
Have a lot to talk about.
How old were you
when you learned
how to read?
Three.
Three?
Who taught you,
your mother?
No, old maester
cressen did.
I had a lot of time
to practice.
My mother kept me
inside because...
What do you call it
in the south,
What happened
to your face?
Greyscale.
What do you call it
north of the wall?
I don't know.
But two
of my sisters had it.
They both died.
How did they cure you?
I don't remember.
I was a baby.
Lots of people came
and tried, i think.
Whatever they did,
it went away.
What happened
to your sisters?
My father made them
move out of the keep
into the huts outside.
None of us were allowed
to go near them.
But we heard them,
especially at night.
They started to sound
not like themselves.
Did you ever see them?
Only once
at the end.
They were covered
with it.
Their faces,
their arms.
They acted like animals.
My father had to drag them
out to the woods on a rope.
What did he do with them
in the woods?
Mother.
Leave us.
Your grace.
You need to stay
away from that girl.
Why?
She's a wildling.
Her name is gilly.
She's nice.
I'm teaching her
to read.
She's a wildling.
Your father defeated
her people.
He executed their king
for treason.
They could strike at him
by striking at you.
Gilly wouldn't do that.
You have no idea
what people will do.
All your books
and you still don't know.
I ordered mance rayder
burned at the stake.
You prevented that order
from being carried out.
You showed mercy
to mance rayder.
A king's word is law.
Perhaps you should ask
ser davos how much mercy
I show to lawbreakers.
Show too much kindness,
people won't fear you.
If they don't fear you,
they don't follow you.
With respect,
your grace,
The free folk
will never follow you
no matter what you do.
You're the man who burned
their king alive.
Who, then?
You?
No.
Only one of their own.
Do you know
this wretched girl,
Lyanna mormont?
The lord commander's niece.
Lady of bear island
and a child of 10.
I asked her to commit
her house to my cause.
That's her response.
"bear island knows no king
but the king in the north,
Whose name is stark."
That amuses you?
I apologize, your grace.
Northerners can be
a bit like the free folk.
Loyal to their own.
I know.
My brother robert
went on often and loudly
About how difficult
it was to control them.
Even with
your father's help.
Tonight, the night's watch
elect a new lord commander.
Ser alliser thorne
is going to win.
Most likely.
Unpleasant man.
He thinks
you're a traitor.
What's your life going
to be like here at the wall
with thorne in command?
Unpleasant, i expect.
Your bravery
made him look weak.
He'll punish you for it.
I don't punish men
for bravery.
I reward them.
I don't doubt it,
your grace.
But i'm a brother
of the night's watch.
I pledged them my life,
my honor, my sword.
I don't know what
i have left to give you.
You can give me
the north.
I can't.
Even if i wanted to,
i'm a bastard,
A snow.
Kneel before me.
Lay your sword
at my feet.
Pledge me your service
and you'll rise again
as jon stark,
Lord of winterfell.
He'll make you a stark
with the stroke of a pen?
It's the first thing
i ever remember wanting.
I'd daydream that my father
would ask the king
And just like that,
i would never be the bastard
of winterfell again.
You deserve this.
You do.
I couldn't be
happier for you.
I'm going to refuse him.
But you'd be
lord of winterfell.
I swore a vow
to the night's watch.
If i don't take
my own word seriously,
What sort of lord
of winterfell would i be?
Crowded. You'd think
we were serving venison stew.
Does anyone wish
to speak for candidates
Before we cast our tokens
For the 998th
lord commander
Of the night's watch?
Ser alliser thorne
is not just a knight,
He's a man
of true nobility.
He was acting commander
when the wall came
under attack
And led us to victory
against the wildlings.
Hear, hear.
He's a veteran
of 100 battles
And has been a defender
of the watch and the wall
almost all of his life.
Aye.
He's the only true choice.
( men cheering,
pounding table )
Ser denys mallister
joined the watch as a boy
And has served loyally
longer than any other ranger.
Through 10 winters
he served.
As commander
of the shadow tower,
He kept
the wildlings away.
We could do no better.
( men cheering,
pounding table )
If there is no one else,
We will begin the voting.
The triangular
tokens count
For ser alliser thorne.
The square tokens
for ser denys mallister.
Each brother will--
maester aemon.
Samwell tarly.
Go on.
Sam the slayer.
Another wildling lover
just like his friend
jon snow.
How's your lady love,
slayer?
her name is gilly.
Brother slynt
knows her quite well.
They cowered together
in the larder during
the battle for the wall.
Lies!
A wildling girl,
a baby,
And lord janos.
I found him there
after the battle was over
In a puddle
of his own making.
Whilst lord janos
was hiding
With the women
and children,
Jon snow was leading.
Ser alliser
fought bravely,
it is true.
And when he was wounded,
it was jon who saved us.
He took charge
of the wall's defense.
He killed the magnar
of the thenns.
He went north to deal
with mance rayder
Knowing it almost
certainly meant
his own death.
Before that,
He led the mission to avenge
lord commander mormont.
Mormont himself chose jon
to be his steward.
He saw something
in jon and now we've
all seen it, too.
He may be young,
But he's the commander
we turned to
When the night was darkest.
( men cheering,
pounding table )
I can't argue
with any of that.
But who does jon snow
want to command?
Night's watch
Or the wildlings?
Everyone knows he loved
a wildling girl
And spoke with
mance rayder many times.
What would have happened
in that tent between
those two old friends
If stannis's army
hadn't come along?
We all saw him put
the king-beyond-the-wall
out of his misery.
Do you want to
choose a man who has fought
the wildlings all his life
Or a man who makes
love to them?
It is time.
It appears to be
a tie, maester.
jon snow! Jon snow!
Jon snow! Jon snow!
You. You.
What have you
got there?
I said--
turn around and go.
Turn around and go.
That's a nice
little sword.
Worth 100 pieces,
a sword like that.
Nothing's worth
anything to dead men.
Come on.
Quickly, go! Go!
Who are you?
Why were they
scared of you?
You lost this.
You said there was
no jaqen h'ghar here.
There isn't.
A man is not
jaqen h'ghar.
Well, who are you, then?
No one.
And that is who
a girl must become.
Why?
mhysa! Mhysa!
Mhysa! Mhysa!
Mhysa!
She should have cut off
the traitor's head
In the great pyramid
and been done with it.
Which is what i keep
telling her to do to you.
mhysa! Mhysa!
Mhysa.
( quietly
speaking valyrian )
mhysa!
I'll stand guard
outside your door
tonight, your grace.
We all guard tonight.
Leave me.
Drogon.
www.tvsubtitles.net